I've decided for this talk to make it a
little bit different.
It's going to be super interactive.
I know literally no one wants to sit for
three fucking hours and listen to people
chat.
So I've segmented the talk into four
areas.
I even actually ditched the presentation
because I didn't want to be like, "Oh, and
here we talk about this." So we've got
what's changed since last year.
I think the biggest objection handling
thing I need
to do is say some of you guys have been to
a talk before, some of you might have
been at the last one, whatever it is.
So let's have a look at that.
What I think is working this year with
some of the guys that are here in my
mentorship and some of you guys
that aren't.
We're going to look at what I think
is going to work for next year.
We're then going to go through some topics
of underrated and overrated.
But not only do we have a Q&A at the end,
every single topic that we discuss,
we're going to take a little break to talk
about.
So rather than you having to wait 25
minutes for me to get back around, "Oh,
any
questions? Oh, yeah, James,
20 minutes ago,
you said about this." Literally
super talkative. Question me,
challenge me.
We can even fight if you want.
We'll just fucking get it out.
To begin with,
so if we look into the first segment of
it, what's changed in the
last year,
the first thing would be my standpoint on
chatbots.
So we have ManyChat is the main one,
and even the guys in
the mentorship,
I've just been fucking around with them.
I'm not even sure how much I think they're
going to make an impact for everyday
people. But in essence,
I didn't realize until last year
that ManyChat is now
kind of a partner with Meta.
So for Instagram and for Facebook, we
can now utilize third-party software to
make it easier for people
to react to our call to actions.
I think we're starting to see some real
fatigue on social media of telling people
to click links in our bio.
It's, "Oh, click the link in the bio."
And people are like,
"I don't work for you."
Like, "What?
You're going to make me go all the way
there?" And another thing is,
when we're in this behavior of scrolling
around on social media, going to someone's
link in bio and ending up on their website
is kind of disruptive to the things that
we're doing on socials. Whereas
if you're in the middle of something,
you can
respond to the chatbot,
DM the word coach or whatever it is,
and then you know that
URL or that call to action
is then going to sit in your inbox over
time.
And Instagram is actually pretty much a DM
platform.
So many of us when we're on autopilot,
we just go to our Instagram, swipe right,
and then look at our DMs.
We actually probably jump into our
Instagram
more to look at what's going on with our
DMs than actually
the posts that are in it. So using
chatbots off the back of carousel posts.
Carousel posts, as well,
put in multiple pictures.
You can put up to 20.
Somebody who did this really well
that I saw was Sean Casey.
When we have content and videos,
we have a bit of a story arc.
We have the hook at the beginning,
then we have some kind of setup,
then we have
the points that we're paying off,
and then we might have an outro
or a call to
action.
But it's really easy to create a story arc
in a carousel.
You start with a picture
that you know in the first two pictures
probably
that's going to be a bit obtrusive,
or it's going to stop people in their
tracks.
So Sean, for instance,
loves recycling the picture of him working
at McDonald's.
Because it's such an unfamiliar
surrounding, they want context,
and the way they
get the context from that
is they swipe through the carousel,
and they don't
realize they're actually being taken on a
story.
And then you go through the lows of,
"Oh my God, I had a drink problem, drug
problem. Now I've got a business.
I retired my parents." You're fucking
going on
that story arc. And then at the end,
he's like, "Oh,
and now I help people get in
shape. Here's my app, Glean.
Click the link in the bio," whatever it
is.
So when we can utilize social media
and get into different positions,
but get people to action the back of it,
I think it's a great thing to do.
So not just providing people with links,
but we can also send people
on very complex,
different threads where people can
interact with the chatbots.
I don't know if I quite like
that so far yet, but
something sneaky I've caught Darren doing,
and I tried this the other day for
James' Academy, and it works really well.
I get people to DM me a certain word off
my story.
You can create a prompt
that gets these automations working.
Could be send me a message,
react to my story, comment the word,
or even actually any comment can get a
reaction from your chatbot.
And Darren cleverly has one where he asks
them to DM something.
It waits 30 seconds,
then he DMs them saying,
"Hold on just one second." And then
he waits another 12 seconds
and does a response message.
So I was like,
"That's fucking brilliant." So I did one a
few weeks ago where they
DM me, and I wait 45 seconds to respond.
I want them to think it's not working.
I want them to think, "Hold on,
this fucking guy just told me to DM him,
and I got
absolutely zero response back from him."
Then I DM them saying, "Hold on just one
second,
mate." Then I wait another 15 seconds,
and I go, "Hold on."
And then I get a video
that I've prerecorded of me getting into a
little booth in
an office that I'm working in. "Hey, mate.
Sorry about that.
Just wanted to tell you about this offer,
this offer, this offer." It feels more
personalized.
It feels more like you're going out of
your way, and I think people
do actually like the idea of being sold
to.
At the end of that automation,
that ended up being 35 messages.
I did tell them it was an automation.
I said, "Oh,
if you want to know about the mentorship,"
whatever it is.
But for us,
I think that whether or not
that sits in our sales funnel of being
part of our
squeeze or our lead magnet,
you could even say,
"DM me the word calories,
and I will give you a breakdown." It
doesn't just have to be a link to a
website.
You can have messages with gaps in
between.
"Hey,
just thought I'd let you know this
is why it's important to count your
calories,
but some things you might have seen
is this is a post that I did
explaining macronutrients. This is this,
this is this.
Oh, by the way, if you
were interested in looking at my prices
for coaching, click
here." The world of interacting with
people as far as an automation has
changed since I stood here
or wherever it was a year ago.
Were we Brighton last year?
So implementing these, it's also a cheap
way of getting engagements with people.
So I think that chatbots
were something I was really against.
I thought it looked really cheap,
but they work, and they're working for me,
and
I'm getting kind of 1,000 responses from
it.
And now we're going to start running a
paid ad initiative as well,
where the prompt
from the paid ad is to get them to hit a
DM rather than clicking a link in a bio.
Some people also will just be inquisitive.
They'll just want to know what happens
when they do send that DM.
We've done it for restocking Nutonic.
Comment the word restock.
Another thing that I've kind of done since
last year is I had a company approach me
that wanted to repurpose my old content
and post it on Facebook.
So my Facebook will do about 1,000 US
dollars a week in revenue from
ads that they place into your videos.
And even if you turn your monetization
off, they still run ads in your videos.
So this company came up, and they
were like, "Hey,
we want to repurpose your old
videos.
We want to make you make more money." I
was like, "Cool." So they've
started going through my old catalogs of
videos, and they've been changing the
dimensions of the videos slightly,
putting the captions in the right place,
and
they've been optimizing my old content to
make money on Facebook.
So our weekly rev on Facebook has gone
from 1,000 to 5,000 US dollars, which
is great.
When I look through my Facebook feed,
I'm like, "Fuck, I didn't post
that. I didn't post that.
I didn't post that." It's these guys
that are doing it.
So I set up a chatbot
that means any person that comments on my
Facebook videos from posts
that I don't even post will get a DM
saying,
"Hey, thanks for commenting on my video.
Just to let you know, I do emails
that help educate people about fitness
and fat
loss. You can get them absolutely free,
and if you don't love them, you can
unsubscribe." So even today,
at this event, we've got this team in
the UK that are ripping off my old videos,
editing them, posting them on my behalf,
getting me paid more,
and those autoresponders
are then converting people to my
email list. So I'm now,
if I look through my AWeber, it's
like 200 subscriptions, 150 subscriptions,
100 subscriptions, 50
subscriptions,
and that's passively growing my email list
while I'm here.
So if you can set up these automations in
place, like these guys came along, they
think that
we're doing them a favor because we share
the revenue with them, but they're doing
us a favor because they're getting my
algorithm moving,
they're getting eyes on my
content, and better yet,
I'm getting people's email addresses off
the back of it.
So that's just great for me.
Then sometimes you have these peaks
and troughs in the
business, and my business partner's like,
"What did you do yesterday?
Because business went well." And I'm like,
"I don't fucking know." But a video
that maybe was posted ago got people to
join my email list, and they got to day 14
in the email sequence,
and then it's just started to generate
sales.
So I think anything that we can do
that means we can just do the effort in
the front part and then people
are nurtured
is the best part. So for me,
that's the bit that excites me.
All of the socials, the creations,
everything I need to do at the front end,
once
that chatbot automation does it,
I can almost let go of it because I know
that I've
done all the work afterwards for them to
either...
In sales, they call it buy or die. Like
if you would like contact someone on the
phone, you're either interested
or I'm deleting you off the sales list.
And I do think in some respects,
we should look at our leads through that.
You're either going to be nurtured to the
point that you want to do business with
us,
or I'm just going to give up on you
because they're either interested in the
business or they're not.
They can either afford your services
or they're not,
they're either right for you
or they're not.
But that takes us on to the next point,
which is something that I was frothing on
when I was doing the course. Frothing
is a bit of an Aussie term, but
autoresponders, which is in essence
when we set up an email sequence that fire
out after we've written them.
So we see these in
loads of different businesses
that have existed for years,
but usually they'll just
follow up,
and there's not really any kind of arc to
it.
So
about 10 years ago,
signed up to a guy's email list,
give me 50 ways in 50 days to
improve my business. I was explaining
that in the course, and I was like, "Fuck,
why do I not have one of these
autoresponders?" So for this mentorship,
I created a 30-day sequence with 30 tips,
bit of advice.
It takes on average between 19
and 24 days to convert people.
So you think that everyone's like, "Oh,
it's a little bit too much." Well, it's
not, and we can see it from the data.
If you can take people on a journey where
you're consistent, you're turning up the
same day,
and you can give some value to
that person, because a lot of us seem
to think that, oh, you post a bit online,
you create a bit of goodwill, you can
just ask people for their email address.
Email address is a very sacred thing to
people, and their email inbox is a very
sacred place where they don't want
clutter.
Nothing's worse than
when you've had a bender, an IB3,
you open your laptop and
there's 58 emails.
But then you like rickle it down,
you're like, "Fuck, there was
only six that actually mattered." So
people aren't just going to give you their
email address, but
if you can get enough value to get in
place for that.
So things I've fucked around with this
year, 30-day email autoresponder for my
business course.
I then wrote a four-and-a-half month
sequence for JSA.
So I was like,
"Fuck it." I got my three books
that I'd already written.
I sat at home,
and I didn't have to write four months of
emails in one day.
I actually just stayed ahead of the
automation. So I just kept adding to it.
So every day, I wrote two emails.
So the automation got further
and further and
further ahead.
So now I'm in a position where I kind of
am flirting with the idea
of retiring from email marketing because
any stuff that I can put in
my fitness bucket on social media,
I can just be like, "Yo,
give me your email address,
and over the next four months,
if I send you an email
every day for four months
and you don't buy,
you're probably not going to fucking
buy." Right?
Four months of turning up every day,
dropping fire.
At that point, I've given up on them.
That's fine.
But in your business,
if you can think about it,
rather than trying to, I call it
like the death of the PDF.
PDFs have been rinsed, and people
are like, "Oh,
download my high-protein PDF guide that's
16 pages."
Even the behavior of people that
are using those lead magnets,
they're not going to
read it,
and I sometimes think there's a danger of
giving someone too much versus
not enough.
If you did an email autoresponder as a
piece of value in that
squeeze or lead magnet series,
they get that one email, and they go, "Oh,
that
was interesting,"
and you turn up the next day.
If you overwhelm people by giving them too
much value, I think they're just not,
"Oh, I couldn't even finish the guy's PDF.
I couldn't even finish this lady's glute
workout mastermind guide.
So how the fuck would I ever be able to do
well on their course?" So autoresponders
are again something where I think
if we can really understand our niche
and our avatar and the person we're
talking to, we can just map out
20, 30, 40 days of problems
and just check in with them every day and
send them a little bit. Now,
they might know that those emails
are automated.
They might know that you've pre-written
them.
But if you can have an impact
and make a relationship with
that person where they
actually feel like, oh my God,
this person's turning up every day to
change my life
for the better,
you're only going to nurture a good
relationship with them.
I was walking down the street in Sydney,
and some guy like fist bumped me.
He was like, "Bro, today's email
was fucking sick." I was like,
"I have no idea
what he's on about." I wrote
that email like three, four months ago.
But to him, it was an email that
was sent today.
So autoresponders, I think,
are a really interesting kind of place
that we're in,
and this technology is over 10 years old.
But it's just something
that can feel a bit novel because
everyone's trying to
really revolutionize what value can I give
to people? What can I do?
But again, if you can make
that sequence right, I mean, how many
people could get 30,
40 pieces of daily content from you via
text and not feel at least a little bit
more obliged
to be in closer to doing business with
you?
And again, 100 people come into
that sequence,
you're only going to nurture some
and push some away.
Does anyone have any questions about
autoresponders before we
move on?
Okay. So let's say,
again, I kind of do a business.
When we were on the phone doing a call,
I was like,
I still...
I didn't know you could massage babies.
All right.
I was like, I'm trying now.
Since I called, I'm like,
if I push this the right
amount, fart.
But then in my mind I'm like, cool,
maybe we have a block of four
email automations.
We could have a prenatal, a postnatal,
and then a one-year
follow-up. So then
if someone comes to you and says, "Hey,
I've had a kid,"
don't send them the prenatal series,
right?
But if someone says, "Hey, I'm pregnant.
I want baby massage," you could then have
maybe a 30-day gap in between it, and
then you might set a 365-day gap. "Hey,
it's me.
I'm just checking in." Or, "A year ago,
I was sending you some
emails about this. It's been a year.
I just wanted to see how you're getting
on.
How's your recovery?
Are you back to this?" Usually,
the ladies that I work with
have at least 75% of their strength back,
whatever it is.
So then, depending on where that person
is in the cycle could be where you bring
them into the automation. Now,
this could become a little bit more
complex.
You might even need to go on Upwork
and find a specialist
that can build out that
automation for you. But again,
if you're a physio, you might have
a prehab automation series
that goes into a rehab automation
series. Or you might have people
that go through a fat loss list and then
might buy a program.
Then you follow up with them in three
months and go, "Hey, how
was your fat loss progress?
How much did you lose?
Just to let you know, on average,
half the people train me for three months,
their
goal shifts to wanting to build muscle,
so here's a muscle growth program." So it
just means where do you put those people
into the funnel?
But if I was you, yeah,
I would segment where
are the people in on their journey,
what information could I give them at
that point?
And then you could run maybe paid ads
or organic ads to then bring them into
that.
So you could run a campaign for a week
saying, "Okay,
did you know that massaging a baby can
help relieve wind?
Did you know that..." Because now I know
with Kim, I'm wiggling his legs
around, trying to get out farts.
What do you think about the windy sticks?
I don't agree with them.
Well, that's a bit of fucking content,
right?
Yeah.
This is a windy stick,
and you should not stick this in your
baby's ass.
Let me tell you why. You know what I mean?
So then at the end of that,
you could be like,
if you want to know how to relieve
your baby of wind,
I can send you a seven-stage guide.
It comes to you by email.
You know what I mean?
So all of these different things.
Are you unsure how to settle your baby?
Did you know...
You told me there
were pressure points on the feet.
I can't remember the pressure points,
but I wish I did now. Do you know what?
This is all content that I need.
When we had the call, I didn't have a son.
Yeah.
But now I do. So even now I'm interested.
I'm like, where the fucking was
that foot massage thing?
My baby's fucking crying,
I just want to go to bed.
So the-
Yeah
... content can be made, and if you
were to say at the end of it,
here is a... The first email could say,
if I teach you everything you need to know
about massaging a baby,
you're going to feel overwhelmed.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to send you one-minute reads
every day.
Within that,
you're going to learn how to do it
yourself.
By the end of it, you could be like,
I do actually do this for a living.
I've given you... This
is one of my favorite things to say.
If I gave you this for free,
imagine what you'd get
if you fucking paid me.
You know?
And it's the same with the business
content on my new smaller YouTube
channel.
If I can give people absolutely so much
value, the first thing they think
about is, fuck me.
If this person does this for free,
what would I get if they pay
me? And again,
it doesn't have to be revolutionary
and different or anything
because a lot of the time
when people pay you,
they've already got the information
they need from you.
They're paying you to make sure they
actually apply it.
And again,
it's why some high-ticket courses where
there is a good return on
investment. For me,
I did a YouTube course.
It cost me £10,000, and I was like, oh,
I best fucking do it or that £10,000's
going to hurt.
Slightly different to the fitness return
on investment.
But again, yeah.
I always just think
that no matter what industry you're in,
what little
frequent emails could you send?
And some people, again, they're like,
does it have
to be daily? Could it be weekly?
Could it be less frequent?
But again,
I like the idea of being there every day.
Doing Neat 24/7.
When you set someone a step count,
it's because even though your client
who's overweight, you say, okay,
I need you to hit the gym three
or four days a
week.
There's still three days a week they're
not training.
So you're like, oh,
how can I remind this person
that they're on a fat loss
journey? How can I remind them
that they're trying to get fitter?
I'll give them something they can do every
day.
It's why people do well on my fitness pal
because they're tracking every day.
It's why they do well tracking their steps
because they do it every day.
I seem to think that success
is a buildup of doing these things every
single day.
So if your emails can be there every
single day, perfect.
And again, people
are going to have the jeans that don't do
up, the boyfriend that chats shit to them,
the person that
disrespected them at work, whatever it is.
If your email lands after their jeans
don't do up, it's perfect
timing. Imagine this. When I
was younger and I was dating,
I wanted to qualify girls quick.
I don't go on a date and then a
date a week later, and then a week later.
I was like, fuck that.
Let me see you on Monday.
Let's do something on Friday,
and hopefully we can bang
by Friday. Why?
Because I'm not getting any younger.
I want to know if we're just a shag or
if we're going to be in a relationship.
And I'll be honest with girls. I say,
"Look." They go, "What
are you looking for?"
I say,
"I just want to sleep with someone twice."
All right. That's all I want.
If I sleep with someone twice,
probably going to make it into a
relationship.
But I want to find out soon.
I don't want to drag it out.
So again,
I would much rather you hammered someone
every day for a month to get
closer to where you
were than trying not to seem too keen.
I like being keen.
I think you should be keen, too.
Your sixth email in the series could even
say,
"Hey. Yeah, me again. Oh,
am I emailing you too much?
Sorry,
I want to change your fucking life for the
better.
If this is too much enthusiasm,
then fuck off and join someone else's
plan." And
the guy who originally did the
autoresponder with me, a guy in
Ireland,
I actually went through his whole email
sequence.
I didn't buy his book. I was a twat.
Fifty-two days, I was like, "Yeah, bro,
cheers
for the tips. Buy a book? Fuck off."
But he added me to his broadcast.
So then he started sending individual
emails after that, and it was fine.
It meant some days I got two emails
or whatever.
But I'll never forget,
and I've said this loads of times in the
course, but he
sent an email drunk after his dad died.
His dad died, went to his dad's funeral,
and he wrote this email, and at the end he
goes,
"If you think it's inappropriate
that I'm trying to sell my book off my
dad's
death,
go fuck yourself." I bought the book.
I was like, wow,
I've never been spoken to like that,
and I like it.
[laughing] So the email side of things,
communicate with people.
Yeah, it's me. It's been 22 days.
When the fuck are you going to do this?
And sometimes you should tell people to
unsubscribe.
Look,
I've seen on the analytics you've not
clicked anything.
Why don't you just fuck off? People
are like, "Who do you think you are?"
[laughing] And they're like,
"I like it." And if they do fuck off,
they're cleaning
your list anyway.
They're getting rid of deadwood
that doesn't want to be in there.
Did you have a question?
Okay, so we've got several platforms.
MailChimp, hate it.
I just think it's shit.
I think it's clunky.
I have to use it for IFS,
and I don't enjoy it.
We've got AWeber, which I love.
It's basic.
It's just text-based.
It's not too complex.
They've got amazing customer service.
I use Klaviyo for my business mentorship
because I'm in partnership with another
company, and Klaviyo is really good.
And then the last one is SendGrid.
My business partner made me use
SendGrid. It's all right.
I wasn't happy to go there because I
grew my list on AWeber, and
when we went to SendGrid,
I lost people's names.
And what you can do in your email series
is when people sign up, you get their
name. You get name, email address.
Then you can put a little bit of HTML code
into your emails so you can insert their
name.
So as you're getting to the end of the
email, and especially putting this in
your autoresponder, you're like, "Listen,
Simon, are we going to fucking do this
or not? Because Simon,
I've been emailing you for 42 days.
Do you want to be a fat cunt or not,
Simon?" And then they know
what's happening,
but seeing your name just gives you a
different emotional
response.
So if you're into abusing people to get a
sale, like I
am, our borderline
was abusing the fuck out of people for
IFS, because I was
looking at the sales and I was like,
"Right. You fucking dumb fucks.
You can come here.
You can learn all of this."
But it's quite therapeutic as well.
I quite like abusing people.
Maybe I've got a problem.
I'm not even sure.
But the emails can be just such a good
place for you to do it.
So I don't send emails from ManyChat.
I don't understand that part of it yet.
I'm still figuring it out.
I actually might one day just hire the
ManyChat
expert and just be like,
"Teach me everything."
But what I would use
is ManyChat to get people to go to the
landing page or the squeeze page
that I want
to collect their email address. There,
yeah, then I take them to the AWeber page,
and it depends what campaign it
is because if it's a B2B campaign,
they're going to
the Klaviyo sign-up page,
and then some wizards
that I'm in business with will
retarget the fuckers. But then
if it's my B2C fitness business,
they're going to
the AWeber page because then they're going
to go into the four-month autoresponder.
But then if it's to get leads for IFS,
they're going to a MailChimp page,
which is
hosted by JamesSmith.life.
So it depends on the campaign, which
is why I prefer just sending traffic,
because that's really what we're doing.
We are just sending traffic places.
And I was on a podcast a few weeks ago,
and the guy's like, "Oh,
so what's it like CEO,
being a leader?" I'm like, "No.
Just because I'm a director in a company
doesn't mean I'm a leader." I'm shit, I'm
disorganized, and I fucking hate admin.
The one thing I cannot handle is staff
or managing staff.
All the people I've hired quit.
I didn't even fire them. They quit.
I've got empty offices at my facility in
Sydney.
They all left, right?
I'm terrible with people.
I've come to realize
that the only thing I'm good at
is sending traffic to a
website. People try talking,
moving forward, with campaigns,
initiatives, with RO. I'm like, "Mate,
just give me the fucking URL.
Just tell me what people you want
and how you want them sent there
and just leave
me to it." NuTonic,
send people to the website.
JSA or AOC,
send them to the fucking website.
That's the bit I like.
We'll grab their email address.
I send an email to send them to the
fucking
website. We are just traffic hounds,
so whichever way you do it best,
that's it, really. Yes.
So depending on how you want to do it,
and we'll get into this a little bit later
in the talk, but say I create a page
that signs up people
and gives me their email
address. I go, "Hey, go to this page.
Give me your email address." Cool.
That's now put into my list,
and I usually only run one list at a time.
From there,
I could either add them to automation day
one,
or I could just broadcast to them.
I can just send them emails whenever I
want.
So for IFS, you just get abused
when I need ticket sales.
But for my fitness business,
they need a little bit more nurturing.
I actually write the first six
or seven emails without selling to them.
So it depends on the person,
the person you're talking to,
and you might want to
make sure that the beginning of the
automation might have more value.
And the reason this is better is
if someone joins your email list late,
they might just get thrown in at the deep
end to a broadcast where you're trying to
be funny, talking about something
that might get a little bit overwhelmed.
I think automations
are great as well because
if you continually build to them,
you're actually creating a marketing asset
that you know that you have confidence
that if one of your posts goes semi-viral,
your email list will have
a bump in uptick,
and they can go on a journey.
People don't like starting a movie where
they miss the first five minutes.
So that's why I've gone kind of back on my
word and I love automations versus
broadcasts.
But then let's say you have a bad day.
You can send a broadcast on top of the
automation and you can start the email
with,
"Yes,
you're probably getting two emails today,
but let me tell you about how shit
my day was." And then you go through it.
At the end of the email,
the only way your day could be worse than
me is if you
don't join my program, is
if you don't give me your money.
70. It's not many. I don't-
Rookie numbers. Got to pump them up.
Yeah, so if you did a broadcast right now,
you could potentially just shout out
loud now and get more people to listen.
Yeah.
But if you started setting up an
automation, you now know that when 10
more people come, 15 people more come,
they're going through it, and the effort
will be worth it,
because that's exactly where I was
when I started a new list.
I was like,
if I'm going to put in all this effort,
I want that asset to be there
so that in a year's time,
it could be double, triple, quadruple.
Whereas if you do just start email
marketing now, you're like, "Ah, fuck,
it's only
70 people." Yeah. If I convert 3%,
it's hardly going to change my life.
How many followers you got?
49. Okay. Still fine. Again, what's that?
5%?
Not terrible. I would just try
and bump those numbers up a little bit.
Even only sending emails to 70 people will
make you better at sending emails to
people. So it's like, oh,
I'm not playing golf this weekend,
so I'm not going to go to the driving
range.
Like, oh, but maybe
if you went to the driving range more,
you might be playing
golf more at the weekend.
So it's one of those double-edged swords
where if you're
just going to use paralysis now because
your email list isn't big, your email list
might never get big because you never
really sent the emails before.
It's all about feedback. So,
I would start sending emails even
if no one was reading them because it's
just
going to make you better at sending
emails.
There's a creative muscle in your mind
that you need to go to.
Paulo Lima just walked in,
one of the most creative minds ever.
I thought- [laughs] ... I thought he
was just an athlete.
But then when I started making content
with him,
he's like Now we need the 35 mil.
We're going to come in at this angle.
You're going to come round.
He watches it back. He goes, "No,
it doesn't look right." Cool.
Ewan, get the 45-millimeter. Darren,
you come out in front.
But that muscle has to be trained.
You don't just wake up being a fucking
director
wanting to make content.
You need to get better at it,
get better at it.
And then he needs edits that go wrong,
and he needs edits that go right,
so he can
get the feedback to know whether
or not that was good.
The real bombs, he goes, "Fuck,
we weren't tight enough in that hook.
We weren't tight enough on
that shot." Another one goes really well,
he gets the
feedback as to why it was.
So I can never imagine a world
or a scenario
where you shouldn't be doing the
repetitions in it.
Aleem has still put the effort into it
when he had no followers,
when he was our mate. When you go, "Oi,
tag me in that, Jimbo.
Oi, tag me in that." Now look at him,
10 million. Shut up.
[logo booming] I don't care about open
rate and click-through rate.
It just depresses the fuck out of you.
I'll write the best email I've ever
written, there's 300 unsubscribes.
I'm like, "Fucking hell,
that's more people that's in this room
now." Don't look,
it's just going to depress you.
Open rates I don't even think are actually
accurate, because
when I go through my inbox,
Darren might have sent a great email,
or Chris Williamson,
he writes the best emails.
I ain't read one in fucking years.
But I stay subscribed to his list to show
support. Do it for Nutonic, brother.
But when I go through
and click on all these fucking...
Ali Abdaal, nice guy,
not reading your emails.
I'm still subscribed, though.
I'm showing love. I click on them all.
I click mark as unread. Mark as read.
But when you mark an email as read,
it comes through as a high open rate.
So I don't think we can look at open rates
as being important.
What I think is important is send emails,
what happens to my Stripe account?
Send emails,
how many people go through to my landing
page?
And we'll get into landing pages in a
second, but another reason, there
are a lot
of people in my mentorship that try
and cut corners with the landing page.
And I'm like, "Please,
just use Leadpages." It's expensive,
but two
scenarios.
If you're getting loads of traffic to your
page and no one's buying, you
have a conversion problem.
If you're getting fuck all people come to
your landing
page and no one's buying,
you have a traffic problem.
And if you don't have the analytics on
your landing page to determine between the
two,
you don't know what to double down on.
Because a traffic problem
and a conversion problem
are two completely different
things. So open rates,
click-through rates, unsubscribe
rates, doesn't matter.
You're just going to depress yourself.
"Oh, but it was really funny
and 30 people unsubscribed." Don't do it.
I don't look. I couldn't tell you.
Okay.
We will have time for more questions at
the end. Okay.
The next point on this
was spotting trends that work
and maybe don't work,
and one thing that everyone in here has
done is created a carousel post.
And it was interesting, because
when I did a carousel post,
you know that's not
being put into someone's feed.
We all started doing reels because we know
that
reels are going to go to cold audiences.
The TikTokification of social media means
that when TikTok came along, suddenly
everything was changed.
None of us scroll on the Following page on
TikTok. We are on the For You page,
because we get more excited about having
content collated to our likes
and needs than we do the subscribers
or the people
that we follow. Same on YouTube.
When you're on your YouTube homepage,
it is not
just the accounts you're subscribed to.
If anything,
it's 80% of the accounts you're not
subscribed to.
So the TikTokification on Facebook,
on Instagram, on everything, means
that social media now
is putting your reel in front of cold
audiences to see how it responds. And
that means that the algorithms of these
platforms can gauge who's interested in
your content.
Carousels do not do that.
You never scroll in through Instagram
and see a
carousel post and go, "Who the fuck
is that?"
But the analytics of how many people of
your existing following
see a carousel post is brilliant,
and actually, you can see now,
you can do this on
YouTube, and you can do it on Instagram.
You can now create posts
that aren't shown to cold audiences,
and you
can even on YouTube actually change a
setting where you post a video and your
subscribers don't get notified. So
if you're ever trialing out a new type of
content on YouTube
and you want to put it out, you go,
"Do not notify my
subscribers.
I only want to gauge this to a cold
audience." But
carousel posts are great because you know
it's only going to your audience.
So you can overshare.
You can use some of your
idiosyncratic personality points
or whatever it is, because
if you try using
something that's a little bit too
outlandish in a reel,
it could fucking bomb.
We've got a lad in the mentorship who is,
I think he's from up north, and he starts
his reel saying, "Hiya,
love." Like a northern.
"Hiya, love." I'm like,
"Stop fucking doing that, mate.
In your town, fine. On the internet,
you're a cunt.
Save it for something else." Carousel
posts at the moment I think are great,
as I
said before, because of that story arc.
And again, you might be tired,
you might be on the plane,
you might be at the
airport.
We always don't have the production we
need to put out a fire piece of
content, but for once,
I'm seeing so many people get such
tremendous amounts of engagement from just
a collation of pictures.
It's almost like we've gone back in time
to Instagram from four years ago, but the
combination of a carousel post with a good
story arc and a chatbot and a call
to action is something
that I think you all should try out.
Because I was very adamant that reels
are good for growth, reels are good for
getting in front of cold audiences,
but now we actually have a tool at our
disposal
for our existing audience,
and I think that's something
that you can very
tactically play on.
I've seen really good combinations with
that.
And again, completely ripped
that off Sean Casey. I was like, "Why
is everyone...
The guy, 'Oh,
I've retired my parents.' Did you?
I didn't see any proof to say that." His
mum's in on it. It's good for business.
[laughing] "Yeah, fucking hell, son,
say what you want." Then Adam Sullivan
copied
him. "Oh, I've retired my mum." Listen,
mate, we're getting bored of it now.
All right? Of course you did.
[logo booming] Up to you.
You can do up to 20 now.
It was 10 before. But again,
I would say whatever feels right.
Here's a golden rule that he taught me,
actually.
And this is the same with any piece of
co...
You are better off being too succinct
and too short than you are going too
long. Exactly the same in email marketing.
In email marketing,
if you have the choice of being 10% too
short or 10% too
long, go too short.
Because the damage
that happens from a message
being too long and people navigating away
from something because it was too
long, I would rather, he says, "You
are better leaving people
wanting more than giving them too much."
Case in point, Andrew Schultz.
Went to go see him live. Amazing.
Theo Von,
thought it'd been 25 minutes too long.
And there is nothing worse than being in
front of a comedian that you really
respect and going, "Fucking hell, mate.
I wish you'd finished 20 minutes ago." I
got ants in my pants. Ruined my night.
These are all things
that changed since last year.
Another thing that I would say I've
changed on is the idea of creating
evergreen
content.
I worked with a creator called Ed,
who does Film Booth and Creator
Booth. He had this massive channel,
and he stopped posting on it.
I was like,
"Why aren't you posting on your channel?"
He goes, "I don't need to."
He's created so many videos
that just sit there,
that he's getting a churn
rate of leads, views,
and just business from a channel
that he no longer
needs to post on. And I was like,
"Fuck." Do you know what we do not get
sold on
enough as fitness coaches?
Is creating evergreen content
that you can just leave
somewhere to do your work for you.
So I've started a new YouTube channel
for business.
I have a YouTube channel for the fitness
stuff.
But what's crazy is,
if you get a good title and a thumbnail,
you can actually just
leave a video and YouTube just works
proactively to get views for you.
I did a video last week,
and seven days after posting it,
it's just started going
off,
and we're getting leads into our business
from it.
And I think that it's very easy to get
caught up with the
Instagram instant gratification.
But I've really got this new invigoration
for creating evergreen content.
For the guys in the mentorship,
they're about to get a course on YouTube,
because
YouTube is a fucking bit of a cunt.
It's so hard.
You do need to go all in on it.
You can't just be like, "Oh,
I'm just going to
dedicate a couple hours to YouTube here
and there." But for any of you that are in
your business and you're getting to a
point where you're starting to free up a
bit
of time, it is something
that I think would be good because the
energy that we're
putting into our socials
and our businesses,
it's only going to fade over time.
And since having a kid, fucking hell,
you're
75% less productive.
So I think we all just need to start
planning for our futures
because some people in here, some
are a little bit younger, some
are a little bit
older.
And if you can start getting excited by
the idea of creating some evergreen
content that can maybe generate leads
and views for your businesses over time
whilst you leave them there,
the second you have the capacity to it,
I see
YouTube as a growing place that's going to
expand over the next few years.
I don't know if you guys agree with me.
Netflix has been shit for six months.
Like, I go on Amazon Prime,
then I go on Apple,
and I'm just navigating
between all of these places,
and none of them are actually
that good anymore.
They're like the odd series
that comes here and it comes online,
whatever.
But now, not even just myself,
but I see it with my missus,
we go on YouTube before
anything else,
and we're starting to use YouTube as our
main way of watching TV and
absorbing content. Now,
if I'm feeding a baby where I know that my
hands are going to be tied up for 30
minutes, I'm going on YouTube,
and I'm looking
for a long piece of content.
I'm looking for something
that I can watch and not
have to worry about.
I don't want to start a new series because
I can't do it
unless my missus is here.
I don't want to do this, do that.
I see a big trend of YouTube being the
place that people go to as the new
TV. So again, as far as moving forward,
wouldn't it be nice for you to make a
fat loss video where, I don't know,
you put a bit of skin in the game,
you do a fat
loss challenge where you cut 11 kilograms
in seven weeks, and it's fucking
miserable and you hate your life,
but you document it really well.
How long did you do 1,200 calories, Trin?
A week. And it fucking sucked, right?
But the post banged. Yeah.
And you were doing the YouTube video on
it. Yes. The YouTube video's up.
It's got about 700 views at the moment.
All right. But you're getting good.
Every time we see a post, it's improving,
everything like that.
But imagine you did a video online,
fat loss challenge, whatever it is,
I did keto
for three months, whatever.
If you could have a call to action in
that video
through your landing page,
your squeeze page, whatever it is,
imagine just leaving
that video there and it just collating
views over time, and then you add another
video to the channel, and you'll find
that people go back and binge it.
I'm trying to envision a world where even
my big
YouTube channel now,
I've completely given up on it,
and it does £2,000 or £3000 a
month in AdSense.
So although that's okay money, that's just
showing you how many views
that channel's getting without me giving
it any love.
I just wish I'd made more content on it
that was in line with my business, and not
trying to go fucking viral talking about
whooping shit.
But
£12,000 from the whoop video. But
we should all get excited about the idea
of creating some form of evergreen content
that we just leave alone
and just generates us views, reels,
whatever it is, and
engagement, because Instagram
and TikTok and Facebook just doesn't do
that that
much. And it becomes very exhausting
when we all become like hamsters on the
wheel.
We work really hard for an asset
and a video, and we post it,
and we just get a
spike for 24 hours.
Then we might repost it again
and get another little
spike. But YouTube's difficult. But
if you guys can get
the capacity into it,
it's an exciting place.
Just
be willing to be depressed
when you put loads of effort into a video
and you think
it's going to go viral,
and then nothing happens, and yeah,
it makes you want to
top yourself. But anyway.
As far as evergreen content,
is anyone out there doing
well on YouTube? Oh, yeah. 700 views,
yeah?
No, I'm
joking.
So I messaged Ed before I did his course.
I said, "Mate,
I've just watched 15 of your videos." He
goes, "Yeah, I did it on
purpose." I'm,
"What do you mean?" He goes,
"That's the exact reason why I created
it." He creates a video.
Then at the end of the video,
he has a hook to go to
another video.
But he actually starts with video one.
Then in video two,
he has a call to action as to why you
should watch video one.
Then he does video three,
which gives you a call to action to watch
video two.
Then you do video two, gets in,
you watch video one.
But imagine if you would,
from a personal training standpoint,
you could do a video
where you watch Jeff Nippard's video on
the best way to do tricep exercises.
You make your own spin that's a little bit
cooler or isn't Jeff Nippard, being
a geek. But then at the end of it,
you're like,
"And that's pretty much all you
should know about tricep training.
But if you're someone
that actually wants big arms,
you're not going to get the
look you want with just training your
tricep.
Which is why I made this video here,
which gives you everything you need to
know
about bicep training." Then you do the
bicep video.
Then at the end of it, you go, "But
when it comes to arm training
and you wear a
T-shirt, the muscle that's out the most
is forearm training.
So watch this video here
and I'll teach you everything you need to
know about
forearm training."
And then the beautiful thing about this
is, on YouTube, the main
score is average view duration. So
if someone watches three of your videos
that are
10 minutes long,
you get a 30-minute score.
And YouTube can go,
"Jesus Christ." Whenever we put people in
front of this channel
and they watch 30 minutes of content,
that just makes YouTube froth and
goes,
"What other people can we put here?"
Because YouTube wants people on the
platform for the maximum amount of time
possible.
So you can try and make a long video.
But the longer the video,
the more complexity it
is in having the story arc.
Trying to keep people engaged 28 minutes
into a video is difficult, and
it requires a certain amount of skill with
editing and things like that.
So if you then wanted to make more
frequent, shorter videos,
as long as you can
keep people engaged in what you're doing,
you can get that average view duration.
But yeah,
I think we should all be excited about the
idea of having content that we
can post and just leave it to do its
thing. Leave it to keep getting things.
And then when you want a bump in the
algorithm, you put another video out.
But as you know, it's just exhausting.
And requires some planning.
So if you're in the infancy of your
business on social media,
maybe don't get into
it just yet. But I couldn't believe
that I kind of just left my channel
to die, and it won't die.
It just won't die.
It just keeps getting views
and videos having upticks.
It's absolutely crazy.
And coming on from that point,
another thing that I didn't really use
last year,
who is posting on YouTube at the moment?
Cool. A few of you.
ThumbnailTest.co.uk.
You see Diary of a CEO, Steven Bartlett,
every hour the thumbnail changes.
There's software that's doing
that for him.
So for the business channel
that I've done recently,
I go on Thumbnail Test
and I had a video that
was generating me a good amount of revenue
for the business,
so I created six different titles for it
where it said, "I made this amount of
money as a PT, as a personal trainer,
as a fitness coach, as a fitness business,
as
a fitness professional," I then change the
title every hour on the hour for
25 days,
so I can get a good indication of what
word is going to
benefit my business the most.
Because PT in America means physical
therapist,
so maybe I do want to use the word
personal trainer.
So for you guys,
you could A/B split fat loss, weight loss,
diet, fat loss hack, fat loss cheat,
and you get to understand,
does the word cheat
work better with your audience,
or does the word hack work better?
Then out of the analytics
that you get from Thumbnail Test,
you can even
see what titles and thumbnails got what
average view duration
or click-through rate.
So if I use the word PT, I
was getting less views, but they were
watching for a longer period of time.
But when I used the word fitness business,
we got more views, but they came and
left the video earlier. And
that level of analytics,
although it can seem
overkill,
I only need to test a video once,
and I now know what word I need to be
using in every single video from here on
in. PT, personal trainer, fitness coach.
This can then help you guys understand
what words, titles,
thumbnails, or whatever
are working with your audience.
Because Diary of a CEO
are just trying to optimize their
thumbnails for clicks, and
then out of those clicks,
they want people that
are going to watch for a long
period of time.
If you're going to spend fucking nine
hours doing a video for
YouTube,
but you won't spend nine minutes creating
several titles,
again,
you're just not really getting the
feedback that you want from it.
Again, the feedback from the emails,
feedback from everything.
You want to see what your audience
responds to so you can cater to that
and double
down on it.
Similarly to the landing pages.
For people that are creating landing
pages, I remember for James Heth Academy,
I created this banging landing page,
and my business partner was like, "Can you
make two more variations of it?" So I did
one that had not a lot of
text and one that had way more text.
And in my mind,
I thought the one with more text would do
better, but the analytics
said it didn't. So I was like,
"Fuck." So he goes,
"Why not make one with no text?"
I was like, "Mate, it's not going to work.
I'll put a video on it,
but it's not going to work.
There's not enough info." Way better.
I was like, "Fuck, these motherfuckers
are watching videos and not reading text."
So I went away and made three more videos.
One was 30 seconds, one was 60 seconds,
one was 90 seconds.
The one that was 90 seconds converted the
best.
So I go away, cool,
I'm going to now make a 90 seconds,
a 60 seconds, and a two and
a half minute video.
So by looking at the feedback
that you're getting from your
audience in certain places,
you can know how to put things together so
that they
remain engaged in it.
And so many people
were just not looking at that.
If marketing departments
are doing it in companies, we can do it.
And again, this software, to use it,
just isn't that expensive.
Anyone use Thumbnail Test at the moment?
YouTube now has it built in,
so you can test up to three thumbnails at
the same
time.
So in the little area where you're
uploading a thumbnail, it can let you put
them in. I don't know if
that technology is good enough yet.
Because if you put the same thumbnail in
three times, it doesn't get a
33/33/33 split.
You'll get one that's like 55
and one that's 25, which just
doesn't make sense
if you do an A/A/A split.
Just some insight into it. Yes?
You don't do it, it does it.
Wouldn't want to do it just for 24 hours,
but you
could get 12 thumbnails changing every
hour on the hour for like
20 days.
So then you have audiences in different
countries, because if I only did
it for one day,
and I posted the video when Australia
are awake and the UK are
asleep,
it wouldn't give me an ideal
representation.
You could get it to change every four
hours, every 12 hours, whatever it is.
But that's why you'll see a Diary of a CEO
episode, and then you go on a little bit
later and you're like, "Hold on,
that's the same person,
but that's a different
thumbnail. Hold on,
that's a different title." They're testing
to see what's
working.
Because if they're going to fly some cunt
from America to sit in front of
Steven Bartlett and chat shit about Huell,
they're going to want to make sure they
get maximalized on it.
And a 10% increase in views for them
is just more exposure to their brand,
affiliates, whatever it is.
So I know it can seem like overkill,
but this shit should excite people,
where they
go, "Oh."
A/B split testing yourself in the
thumbnail versus not being in the
thumbnail.
Because a lot of us seem to think we need
to be in our thumbnails, but maybe the
analytics says so, maybe it doesn't.
And then you know what to keep doing from
there on in. Fucking hell.
This was supposed to be like a five-minute
segment about things that were different
from last year.
Yeah, so even with old videos,
you can change it.
So there's a guy in Sydney who
is a YouTuber. He's called Marcus.
So I sit with Marcus,
and he says to me, "Oh,
show me this high-converting video that
you have." And it was a webinar
that I did maybe a few months ago for the
mentorship, and I called it
Sales and Marketing Masterclass Webinar.
And he goes, "Bit of a shit title,
isn't it?" And I went, "Do you know what?
That is a shit title." And it
was me in the thumbnail with a thing
that said
Webinar, and he was like,
"It's a shit thumbnail." I was like,
"Do you know what?
That is a shit thumbnail." And he goes,
"No offense, but I can't believe you would
have such a shit title
and thumbnail on
that webinar you did." He's like, "If you
put a better title and thumbnail on that,
it could do a lot better." So I was like,
"Okay." And he showed me a guy in Dubai
called Charlie who has the most
chaotic thumbnails ever,
where he just gets screen grabs from
different things and
put them together. So I actually went
and took some random screen grabs from
Google
Images, a picture of myself,
a Stripe account,
and then there's like a Venn
diagram to something to do with makeup.
I just took the first Venn diagram I
could.
It doesn't even make sense
if you look at the thumbnail.
I put it up,
and I changed the title to say, the
lifetime of JSA has done like $13 million
or something in the Stripe.
So I screenshotted that, and he goes,
"Make the title How I Made $13 Million so
you
can steal it," put it in brackets.
And he goes, "Now take the I when talking
about yourself and make it lowercase."
And it's actually really difficult to do a
single I lowercase anywhere on your
computer because it thinks you
shouldn't be having a lowercase I
if you're talking about yourself.
He goes,
"Make the title look like you don't give a
fuck. Lowercase I." Cool.
Sean, one of my business mentors goes,
"James, one of your old videos did $3,000
this week. Why is that?"
And you can see where my video died.
I changed the title and thumbnail, boom,
and it's still climbing.
Now I've got people on your YouTube Studio
going, "Hey, bro, got so
much
knowledge out of this.
What an amazing webinar." It's like a
four-month-old video.
So yeah. And he said to me,
"You're better off over-delivering
in your title and thumbnail,
but at least getting some fucking views,
because if
the video's dead,
no one's watching it." So definitely play
around with it, see if
you can learn from it same time.
All right.
The next segment we're going to look into
within this, I know we covered off a few
things there,
but we're getting into some of the
nitty-gritty stuff now.
What's working in 2024?
If we look at the landscape of creators
around us,
what is kind of like trends that
are working?
The first one has to be hooks.
Now,
the hook is the first thing we say in a
video, and so many people are still
butchering this, where you might try
and introduce yourself, or you
just kind of waffle a little bit. Now,
there are different types of hooks that we
can be using. Statement hooks,
where you say something as it is.
Question hooks,
where you pose a hook to someone.
We have visual hooks,
where we can show something to someone.
Maybe it's a prop, maybe it's an analogy,
maybe it's a metaphor.
This glass of Skittles represents this,
whatever it is.
We can then have hooks where we show
people a preview of what's to come,
which is often found in longer form
content,
or if you had a skit of some kind or
anything like that. Have you ever seen
if someone's playing a prank in the street
on the TikTok,
they'll actually take the response from
the person, use it
as the hook,
so then you watch the video to get the
context of what's just
happened.
We need to really strategize what we're
doing for the first three, four
seconds of a video, because
if we look at the behavior of people
absorbing content,
the majority of us, if I
was to hazard a guess,
wake up,
try not to use our phones too much.
Any digital interaction's going to be
business-led, whether it's emails, Slack,
Discord, whatever it is.
We then manage people in our networks,
clients,
whatever. Then as the day goes on
and as we start to get a bit more
exhausted and a
bit more fatigued,
as the evenings come round,
we start getting into that dopamine
chasing,
getting to bed. You're like,
"We could watch another episode of
'Breaking Bad,' or
why don't we get into bed an hour earlier
and just scroll the fuck out of TikTok?"
Yeah, sold. And you get in there,
and you're there with your partner in bed,
boom, boom, boom, boom. Oh,
look at this dog.
This dog's so cute. And my missus
is crying.
I'm like,
"Why are you crying?" She's like, "Oh."
Sometimes she'll get upset seeing
someone's TikTok about their dog dying.
And then you'll see her at the end of the
bed kissing our dog, mourning his death
when he's not even died yet.
But you're there, and your finger is
literally only giving people two
or three seconds before you're onto the
next one.
If you only give other creators a couple
seconds to impress you, why do you think
other people would give you any more time?
So whether it's being inquisitive,
whether it's moving props,
whether it's having
questions, whether it's having statements,
you really need to try and analyze
what it is that people
are doing to get you in there.
There's one guy on social media who's
massive, who
unboxes things for a living,
but his hook is always spinning the box,
and
he sniffs it.
And what you're looking for is context.
He's like a Mexican guy.
He'll spin a box with a TV in it
and then be like [sniffs]
, and then he starts unboxing it.
And the first time I watched it, I
was like,
"What the fuck is going on?"
But that's exactly what he wants me to
think.
If he was there like, "Hi, my name's Tony.
This is a Samsung 85-inch Octavia TV,
and you let"
You're like, "Fuck off, mate.
I don't care." But just having something
that's a
little bit nuanced to it. Sean Casey
is the very nuanced, like
monotone. He's just there. People
are like, "Hold on.
Is this guy for serious?
He's not even got any facial expressions."
It works for him.
Adam Sullivan is roundhouse kicking the
fuck out of something.
Whatever it is that you can do to just try
and get people's attention those first
few seconds, and
intrigue is going to be probably the best
emotion that you want to captivate from
someone with your hook.
That's actually what YouTube titles
and thumbnails
are looking to do, is to build intrigue.
So rather than going,
let's think about it in
a fat loss context. You wouldn't be like,
"Use this method to lose six
kilograms." You'd be like,
"How this man lost six kilograms in three
days without having to restrict
calories." You're like,
"How the fuck did he do it without
restricting calories?"
If you can create some kind of intrigue,
that's where you're going to get the
response from people to give you a little
bit more time.
So when it comes to recording,
whenever you get the camera going,
you're there in
front of the camera.
Sometimes I go in front, and I'll be like,
"When it comes to
doing Instagram Reels, there
are three types." And I'm like, "No,
it's not good
enough." And then I come back,
and then I'm like,
"When it comes to Instagram
Reels, you need" Oh, fuck. I'm like, "No,
it's not good enough." I literally, if
you look at my edit before I've done the
edit, it's just me fucking up.
Declan, he's there. I'll say something,
and I'm just like, "It's not good enough."
And then I'll be there sat in silence,
and I'll just be there in front of the
camera rolling, and I'll be like,
"This is why your Instagram Reel sucks."
Cool. Right.
And then I'm thinking about the next part
of the Reel. Just give it several goes.
You can actually have three
or four different hooks in your video.
Maybe you plan it out.
Maybe you strategize it a little bit.
Something I've definitely got a little bit
better at recently is actually trying to
script videos. I used to think that I
was like, "Oh, I don't need to
script vid" Like Darren, for instance.
Is he gone?
That guy needs to be more organized.
If he just scripted what he
was going to say in his videos,
he would have a much
nicer car than he does. All right?
But we're proud, and we think, "I have a
good brain, and I'm smart,
and I've got followers on social
media." When it comes to just typing,
I will type things and go, "Fucking hell.
That's impressive.
That's almost like too smart to come out
of my brain," but it
came out.
When you're trying to articulate
something, sometimes you have these
different blocks,
the camera's in front of you.
If you can just go somewhere that's
chilled, maybe it's a laptop,
sat in a Pret,
whatever, you can just type out hooks
and go, "Oh, take that out.
Oh,
it's a little bit too long," whatever it
is.
Again, so many of us
are putting so much effort into the
fucking video.
Jayden might have even done 1,200 calories
for fucking seven days, but then he only
spends three minutes doing his hook.
I'm like,
"Where's the discrepancy in effort between
that?" But if you can just
work on it, look what works well,
and again, when you're absorbing content,
don't let these people just trick you into
watching their videos.
Be like, "Hold on a second. What
magic just occurred for me to end up 19
minutes into this fucking
person's video? What was it
that this person said that means I'm now a
diehard fan for them?" Even
if you look at, anyone following Matt
Armstrong on YouTube,
guy who's currently fucking dominating it,
buys crash-damaged cars Have you seen him?
Daz Lamar?
We're going to talk about him in a little
bit.
His videos always start with him getting
into a car and slamming the door and
talking to the camera,
and he's setting the scene of his
hook with being in a car.
And every single video I'm like, oh, it
must work. It's just the way
that he's setting context so
that people understand
what he's talking about.
But we actually have a lot to learn from
Matt Armstrong a
little bit later.
None of you saw the guy
that bought Marcus Rashford's crashed
car? He's a fucking wizard, bro.
This guy's a fucking wizard,
and everyone thinks
he's just a mechanic. He
is a master storyteller, and
something he's done right,
he creates one-hour-long videos of these
cars
that he's fixing,
and they're getting one to two million
views in the first 12
hours.
Then he created a Mark II YouTube channel,
where he puts all
of the videos together.
So he has a four-hour YouTube video,
and he puts
them on, and they're getting 18,
19 million views because the average view
duration
is so massive between them. But anyway,
we won't get too carried away with that.
But that guy, he's making- Wedge. Wedge.
Spent 200 grand on a crashed car. Wedge.
Okay.
We spoke a bit about the avatar behavior
and understanding where the people are
that you're doing content in front of.
Another thing that's working in 2024,
good production. Good.
I think that making content on an iPhone,
those days are coming to an end.
Even though the iPhone cameras
are amazing, I set like a minimum,
I hope you don't
mind. Even the DJI Pocket Osmo 3.
Everyone know about
this camera? So this camera films in 4K.
It doesn't look as good as a Sony A73
or anything else, but
these... Do you mind if I like?
So it's got a battery pack on it at the
bottom,
which you can use to charge. But this
is just a really easy camera
that you can use
for content. This also will track you,
so if you're doing any movement stuff in
the
gym. Also,
if you have an iPhone in front of you,
when you're
trying to do an Eddie Habru in a fucking
shopping supermarket like, "Oh, yeah.
Hi, mate. Yeah. Yeah, do it again, mate.
Yeah." It's a bit invasive.
Or if you go in with one of these fucking
cameras to the supermarket, yeah, nice
one, brother. But these
are actually great because not only do
they have a gimbal
in it,
which means it has really good
stabilization,
you can also just film on the
sly,
and people don't even know you've got a
fucking camera in front of them.
Also means that if you're in the gym,
you could just maybe stick
that up onto the
squat rack and just have it track you
around. It's not invasive.
It's not like getting in people's faces.
Also, the stabilization on this,
that you can move it without it getting
jittery or
whatever, these are great.
You can also film in portrait when
you're using it, so
that you can film landscape portraits,
whether you're doing
YouTube, you're doing reels,
whatever it is. These also come...
Oh, fucking salesperson.
I should be on telesales.
I should be on a shopping channel.
Get your DJI Pocket Osmo 3.
It also comes with a mic
that connects to it, so you can use it.
Although the audio on it is great.
These are not that expensive.
How much did this cost you? £700? £600?
£500.
So you already have the mic,
so you got the one without, cool.
There's someone here, Kate Orishi,
who's trying to pin me down for a podcast.
Darren goes, "Mate,
I just did a podcast with this chick." Did
the podcast, then
afterwards she goes,
"Let's do it on video." He went,
"What do you mean let's do it
on video?
We just did the podcast." She was like,
"Yeah, yeah, I'll ask you the
same questions, but on video." I'm like,
"What?"
Any time you film, right? So let's say,
for argument's sake, this is an external
microphone. Let's say, actually,
I've actually got an external microphone.
When you have a microphone like this one,
you can just
use it to record an audio file. Then
if you have dog shit audio on
this, in any editing software,
whether it's DaVinci, Premiere Pro,
whatever it
is, you can just press synchronize,
and it will take your good audio,
and it will
line it up with your shit audio.
Then you just drag it over the top,
and you now
have amazing audio.
Similarly to whenever you're doing like a
podcast or there's
any media production, you know
when people clap in front of the camera
or they have
that little director's thing?
[clicks tongue] That's so you get a spike
in the
audio,
so it makes it easier to line everything
up, so that the audio and the video
are in the same place. Look at that.
Every day is school day.
And also,
because you would've seen in my content
for ages ago
that I would've had like a little magnet.
You would've seen
that little square magnet thing on my
chest.
Everyone thought it
was just my T-shirts because I had a
microphone underneath.
But now I've been fucking with,
because I just absolutely froth good audio
content,
I've actually taped a microphone to the
underside of my vest, so it just
looks better in content.
I want people thinking,
"Where's the fucking microphone,
brother?" There's one there, I know.
But for everything else.
When it comes to
getting into production,
I think everyone should aspire to at least
have a camera
that's built for purpose to do it.
Because the iPhone
is to do so many different
things,
and although it's great for taking
pictures, stabilization, exposure,
things like that, these are just great.
For any of you that have got an editor,
you can also film in log.
Log means that it looks like dog shit,
but it means that when your editor starts
manipulating the colors,
they can make it look sexy as fuck.
Again, when it comes to price,
you don't even need to know what you're
doing to use
this. Whereas with these things,
you've got F-stop, exposure.
What's the other one? ISO? ISO, F-stop,
exposure, shutter speed.
There it is. And then everyone's like,
"What does that mean?" When you start with
cameras, it doesn't fucking stop.
So the real camera guys are like,
[laughs] "You film in auto mode?"
You're like, "Yeah, well,
I haven't got a videographer." They're
like, "Pathetic."
When you film in auto,
it's not getting your ISO right.
It's not getting your F-stop.
A lot of cameras have the manual focus
thing where you can turn off the auto
focus. That's what the OGs do.
They get you in line, do it all.
But anyway.
You can tell I obsess about this stuff,
and this is why I have no staff.
[laughing] Getting a good camera quality,
I see it over and over again,
where I say to people, I'm like, "Look,
the content's getting better,
but the way it looks isn't."
And I just think, honestly,
getting one of these,
or something similar, is so much better.
Because when you buy one of these cameras,
you're also reducing the barrier to do
content. You could literally be like,
"Mum, hold that," and she
can't fuck it up. She cannot fuck it up.
You give your mum an iPhone,
she's recording her own face
while she's supposed to
be doing stuff with you. So yeah,
really good.
Even the built-in audio to these
is great and they're versatile.
You can even use them as webcams.
And yeah, thank you very much. Which
is that one?
Sorry? That one? Yeah. DJI
Pocket Osmo 3.
Another thing you can do as well
is, let's say you want continuous audio,
but you don't want continuous video.
You can also press
and hold the record button and
Or maybe not on this
one. There you go.
When the red light's on,
that's now recording as a
microphone device. So, in essence, if
that red light is on,
irrespective if that camera died right
now, this will still take audio, and this
now works as if it's an external
microphone.
So let's say you're recording someone
and you're worried they're going to go out
of
range because there's a receiver on
that camera, this is a transmitter,
it would be
fine.
It would still have an audio file on that.
So let's say your worried your Mrs.
is cheating on you.
You could get that, get the red light on,
hide it in her bag when she goes to work,
come home, listen to the whole thing.
I fucking got you, bitch.
I got you, a fucking MP3. Just saying.
Don't use an Air Tag, though.
It notifies them.
[logo whooshing]
As far as effort,
me clipping it here to here is
2% more effort. To me, it looks better,
right? Imagine this.
Say me and you are doing a reality TV
show, right?
And we're going to put it on YouTube,
and we want to sell it to BBC
or Channel 4,
or even we're doing a movie, right,
and we're invited on set.
Can you imagine in any fucking world
that you were to watch a film
and you're like,
"Hold on,
I can see the microphone." You'd go,
"You lazy fucking cunts.
You lazy fucking cunts." So for me,
I'm like, I'll be honest with you,
I want to over-exceed the level of quality
that I need to do.
Maybe 1080p with a mic on my shirt
is fine,
so I'm going to film it in fucking
6K,
and I'm going to get Declan to change the
log files to make it look sexy as
fuck,
and I'm going to hide the mic so they
don't know where it fucking is.
I want to be over-delivering on
everything.
I want people to watch my videos and go,
"Fuck, this is better than it should be."
Because with so many people all doing
and saying the same thing, it could be a
point of difference to differentiate
between people.
[logo whooshing] If I tape it to my chest,
we get a bit of rub, but
if I tape it to the T-shirt, we don't.
So I was doing a shoot for New Tonic in
Vegas, and when they clipped it on
and went
under my shirt, I was like,
"I could be doing this." And this, again,
is
Alima, right?
Does so fucking well because he does his
skits with
too much attention to detail.
That motherfucker gets a
skit and waits five months until he's in
New York to do the reaction.
He goes to New York to do a skit.
The guy has filmed
maybe eight,
nine skits in Ibiza already because he
knows if he was to
record the reaction in the wrong place,
it wouldn't do as well.
When you watch Alima, he literally
is obsessed of getting every single
angle of it right,
and that's why he's just surpassed 10
million followers,
because whatever level you think you need
to be at, you should try and go above it.
And I think that that,
even technically, I'm a PT,
I shouldn't know about all the
camera settings.
I shouldn't know about how to edit in
DaVinci and Premiere.
But for me, I think it's
that attention to detail of the really
small stuff that
helps me do well.
Because I know everyone else
is just sleeping on it.
I go see a competitor, I'm like,
"I can see your microphone, dickhead."
So, yeah, it's fun to me, I suppose.
I've got mental problems with stuff. Yes.
[logo whooshing] Kayla at Scenes makes it
look
like she's filming her front room.
I've been there.
It's a fucking studio the size of this
room-
Yeah
... to make it look like a front room.
I think it's always good to go to
that level for your followers because I
think
people like to see the effort
that you go to.
Even when people,
let's say you're doing a video about your
day and you go to the
gym. They go out their house,
they put a camera on a fucking tripod,
they go back
in their house,
they close the fucking door,
they open the door, they walk to their
car, they go back,
they close the fucking door,
then they go to the tripod, they
take the phone off the tripod,
they take the tripod back in,
fucking hell, and they
go back, just for two seconds of footage,
but it looks nice.
I remember I was watching "Peaky
Blinders," and there's a scene in it where
four of
them are walking down the street,
and there's pyro and shit going off in the
background. I'm like, "Four actors,
Cillian Murphy,
pyro, health and safety, street. There
are two cars that are 100
years fucking old there
that have got to be hired.
They've got to be there.
Not to mention the insurance policy they
would need to have a car of that age next
to that pyro.
It's a two-second fucking scene.
Probably cost £115,000." There's going to
come a time when maybe you can't
differentiate with someone else.
Maybe they are the same level of content
creator than you, and maybe it is the
subtle differences. 2017,
my business partner, me and James Shaw,
we had complex accounting.
Neither of us were Australian residents.
JSA was absolutely pumping.
Our accountants were like,
"Stop making money because
you haven't got your business set up." We
go into the city, and we meet with
PwC and Deloitte,
two of the biggest top four accountancy
firms.
We go to Deloitte, sit with them,
everything's great,
and our sign-on with them is
about £30,000,
just to start the accounting.
Then we go to Deloitte.
We went to Deloitte, then we went to PwC,
and I came out,
and I go,
"Who are we going with?" He goes,
"We got a biscuit with our coffee at
PwC, so we're going with them." That
was it. That was the difference.
I fucking cracked up. He was like,
"They were both the same.
They were both charging the same amount.
They're both big four accountants.
We got a biscuit with our coffee here.
We'll go with them." So
that's the way I see it, right?
The little bit of effort.
The fact that my accountant, even now,
when I message him
something that could be a little bit below
the book, he goes, "Let me call you
after work." He calls me out of hours
because he goes, "We can't have this on
email." Right? And I think,
"Do you know what?
I'm going to stay with this guy for years
because he's going above and beyond the
level of service he needs to
or he should do,"
and that's what I vibe with.
So, yeah.
It doesn't really answer your question,
but at
the same time, it does.
You should be aspiring to make the nicest
production
possible because if you started watching
something on Netflix or you were to buy
something like a TV series, and there
were just some shortcuts taken in it,
you'd
be like, "Come on, I'm invested in you.
I want this back."
And every single social media video
that you make is
an asset for your business and brand
that you're putting out there.
I just don't understand why you wouldn't
maybe get the backdrop.
Yeah.
All I want you to do
is obsess them with getting a little bit
better.
Yeah.
Right? I'm a brown belt in jujitsu. I
was very happy at purple.
I was very happy at blue. I
was very happy at white.
Although I was dog shit, the reason I
was happy was because I
was getting better.
I never think to myself, "Oh,
you fucking idiot, a blue belt,
trying to do a
normal plateau from here." I don't care
because every single time, the reason that
I'm content with where I'm at
is because I'm improving.
And all I'm saying
is start with the jump cut,
start with the iPhone, start with
the tripod.
Get the camera up because now things
are going to get a little bit
better.
Then you're going to film at home in your
front room, through your means or
whatever it is.
Maybe we do get the backdrop.
Maybe we do get the light.
We're just continually taking small steps
forward.
I've made more progress in my own probably
personal brand in the
last 12 months than the nine years before
it I
feel like when I look back at my last IFS
talk, I'm like, "This guy's a fucking
idiot." It was a year ago. Honestly,
I'm embarrassed by the quality of stuff I
put out,
only because I want to make sure I'm keep
improving and getting better.
So that's all I'm asking.
Never use the word perfect.
Imagine this,
I've been doing podcasts for fucking six
years.
I send him a podcast every day.
I need a speech coach.
I keep using the word like.
I don't know where it's come from.
Ten years into my career,
I've started going backwards.
I keep using the word like,
and to the point I can't listen to the
podcast.
So ten years into this,
I'm still finding issues and
problems that I'm facing,
and all I'm going to do
is just try to say like less.
There's no way I'm going to get it out in
the next podcast that I go on.
So yeah, never look for perfect.
Only look for better.
When you say,
it's obvious you say you need to progress
in things like editing and
making cooler videos,
where would you think
that balance would be
maybe I should just hire somebody who's
better at editing-
How much better have you got at making
videos in the last two months?
A lot better.
Yeah.
You were doing static pictures before.
There were no reels.
I'm watching your content get better.
Don't worry about that.
Don't worry about hiring someone,
because in six months you'll be a fucking
weapon.
Look at Lucy Lord. Don't know
if you follow Lucy Lord.
Her content looks professional. It's her.
She worked in pharmaceuticals.
She used to sell drugs to vets.
But she just consistently got better to
the point
that people now think someone else
is doing it.
Yes, there comes to a point
that maybe you hire someone,
like I have Declan now,
but even I did the first eight years
without it.
So, I still always think
that you should become the expert,
and then you can always
have help when you want.
But I don't like offsetting too much of
the
creative stuff to you, because then
that muscle becomes atrophied,
and you never want that.
You never want to walk into a room
and not know the angles
that you want. So there comes a point,
but I would say try and
maximize to become the best version of
that content creator that you can.
And the more that you start seeing things
that work, you then start to see it in
other people's content,
and then you start to emulate it yourself.
Emulate is just the word we use to copy
other people, right?
Which is what we're all doing.
Even my business mentorship
is very similar to the one
that I fucking studied in six years ago.
And his is probably similar to the one
that he did four years before that.
We're all just putting our own spin on
stuff anyway,
but the more creative you can
be with it, the better. And I think
that it's going to be the most creative
person
that kind of
flips content that's going to do better
from it.
You're not the first dietician to make
nice food. You know what I mean?
Okay. We're still almost working in 2024.
We spoke before about good landing pages,
okay?
I butt heads with a lot of people about
landing pages and sales calls, but, hey,
that guy spent six grand on dinner last
night.
He didn't need to call the restaurant to
be sold to.
He just wanted to go, know what
was on the menu, and let's fucking do it.
Same.
When you walk past a restaurant,
when you're walking past,
let's say we're in
Ibiza, whatever, cool. First thing you do,
menu.
Is this the cuisine for me? This
is what people are doing
when they're watching you
on social media.
Imagine you see a menu with no prices,
you're like, "Fucking
cocksuckers." Right? No chance.
You might want to look to whether
or not the
restaurant's busy, which
is another reason I don't like sales
calls, because if
your diary is open every hour for a sales
call, you've got an empty restaurant.
They're getting food poisoning.
Get the fuck out of there.
As the owner of the restaurant,
you should not try
and sell people into it.
You should come over, "Hey, my friend,
I have a great place for you." Cool.
"Here's a menu. Let me know
if you need anything."
That's it.
If the guy comes over with the menu
and goes, "Hey, my friend.
Good restaurant.
Come on, come on, come on. Come here,
come here, come here, come here." You're
like, "Fuck off, mate.
We're going somewhere else.
I don't like this." And I feel
that the landing page just needs to be the
same.
What it is you're offering, what they get,
why they need it, how much it costs.
That's what we're doing
when we're looking at menus.
People just want to know.
And again, some people
are going to go there
and they're going to bounce, but
again, if you've got a fucking butcher's,
you shouldn't give a shit about
vegetarians or vegans. Someone's like,
"Oh, you're killing animals." Fuck off,
you're never going to buy my sausages.
You know what I mean? It's not a problem.
A well-designed landing page
is a place that people can go to
and handle their own
objections. I still will concede
and say to people,
if you want to leave your
contact information there,
don't have it so you can never have my
number.
Because this average customer for you
might actually be worth thousands of
pounds over the course of however long
they stay.
But ultimately,
I think we should all be looking for a
world where you send traffic
to a page and customers pop out.
If they're unsure, there is
nothing that can be done on a sales call
that can't be done in an email.
And people that even from my course,
they message me, they're like, "Oh, James,
you
know,
I've used a lot of business mentorships in
the past, and basically, I did the
thing with Tony McCleary, and then,
I got in a legal battle,"
and I don't even read
the email. I go,
"Have a fucking one-month money-back
guarantee.
Bye." That's it.
I've now handled every objection
that they have.
They can either join or they might not,
whatever.
The landing page should do the same.
The best thing that I've actually started
getting people to do now more is to have
what's known as a VSL,
a video sales letter.
A video front and center of your fucking
sales page because let
me tell you this,
so many of the girls I've been on dates
with on Hinge back in the
day are fucking minging.
And they're minging because photos do
not paint a picture,
and you cannot tell enough about it.
There was the Rory Sutherland guy who made
a great point on Chris's podcast where
he goes, "Jennifer Aniston
and Cameron Diaz are not fit enough to be
supermodels. The real attraction
is in when you see them move." When you
see Jennifer Aniston interact with some of
her friends, you're like, "Oh my God,
she's so fit." Same with Cameron Diaz.
When she smiles and flicks her hair,
you're like, "Oh my God." There are some
people that are only beautiful
when you see them in motion.
Now,
when you guys post pictures on your
landing page of the photo shoot that you
did in the studio with the Rembrandt
lighting and the oiled up fucking [mimics]
it's not a representation of who you are.
And so much of the time,
I would not go on a date with a girl
unless I could see
them move. If I could see them talk
and interact with their friends,
it would paint
a picture. So
even if you're shit on camera,
it can actually be such
almost like a pleasant thing.
They see someone nervous out there trying
to do their
business, they're like, "Fuck,
I can relate to this person." Because
sometimes if
you are too confident on camera,
they don't resonate with you.
"Oh, this guy's a pro. I don't want a pro.
I just want a personal trainer to help me
do my fucking workouts," whatever.
You should have at the front
and center of that you,
and do not get caught up in making your
landing page about you, because no
offense, no one gives a fuck about you.
In the nicest way possible. "Hi,
my name's John,
and I swam for County." No one
cares. "Hi,
I've been a physique bodybuilder." No one
cares.
"Hi, I've been a p--" No one cares.
They care about themselves.
Everyone just cares about themselves,
and the better you can understand that,
the
better.
So when you start your VSL video on your
sales page,
just start talking about them.
"I create this program for people
that want to lose
weight.
I do that by producing this service
that they get, and it costs this
amount. Now,
I know you're probably going to say that's
quite a lot, but it's worth
noting that I will check in with you every
single day over WhatsApp.
The reason I use WhatsApp is, well,
it's where you check in with your friends
and
family.
There's no point in me creating a very
complex app that's going to make
your life more difficult,
because my job is to help you get better
without making
your life more difficult. The prices
are down below, but it's worth noting that
before you think it's really expensive,
I do have a money-back guarantee, which by
all means you can take the complete piss
with.
But the way it works out
is the majority of people
that sign up to my program stay
with me,
so I don't mind offering you that.
If you have any questions,
I have left my phone number
and my email address down
there. Feel free to waste my time,
whatever it is.
I hope you enjoy the program,
and I'll see you soon.
Oh, and if you do want a sales call,
I don't do them.
I'm a very busy professional.
But I tell you what I can do is
when you buy it,
we'll do an onboarding call as the
first part of it anyway,
so I look forward to seeing you on the
call.
Cheers." Boom. Sell it to them.
Don't get distracted about anything else.
Don't tell them about your credentials.
Don't tell them about anything.
Just sell them the fucking course.
Because ultimately,
that's what people want.
When people arrive on my landing page for
my business mentorship, they don't care
about how much money I've made.
They don't care about how many followers I
have.
They don't care about how many books I've
sold.
They want to know what information I have
that they can put into their
businesses.
Even the reason you're at this talk,
it's not really because you
like me,
it should be because you like your fucking
businesses, and you like your
lives,
and you want to leverage my fucking
knowledge to help yourselves, and that's
fine.
Because I will also leverage your
positions to sell some of you into my
mentorship.
We're all just trying to fucking help
ourselves, and the better you can
understand that,
the better you can actually help people.
Because if you foolishly think
that people care more about you than they
actually do,
you'll make it harder for yourself to sell
to those people.
It sounds like a really fucking selfish
thing to say, right?
But you know people
that spend all their time giving money to
charity? Selfish.
They're only doing it to make themselves
feel better.
It is.
The only reason, oh,
you see a homeless person,
and you're like, "Oh, have £10."
Why? Because I'm a generous-- No.
Because it made me feel good.
Fucking hell, I feel great.
I might do that more often.
You know what I mean?
Make the sales page about them.
Not about you, about them.
And it's your job to disarm them,
dismantle any hesitations
they have,
and you might feel like a sleazy fucking
sales douchebag,
but if there's a money-back guarantee
and you actually honor it, you
can't do much else for them. Landing page,
make several versions of it,
A, B, C, split test it,
one with more text, one with less,
one with different
videos, whatever it is. Even Jayden,
I'd go to you on your landing page to just
face the facts that you
are a baby-faced motherfucker.
You went, "Let's just get into it.
I know I'm really young,
but the good news is, I
don't charge the world because I still
live at home with my mum." Perfect.
You know what I mean?
Disarm them before they're there,
because they're going to
think,
"Why am I paying this guy fucking £55 a
week?
He doesn't even pay rent." [laughing] You
don't pay rent.
You do pay rent, but still,
you know what I mean.
So,
I think this is the most beautiful way to
do it.
Rather than Jayden going,
"I've been a fitness coach
and a fitness enthusiast now
for three and a half years." Just be
honest with people, just be real,
and I think
that's one thing that's really lacking in
the industry.
Everyone's trying to make it too much
about themselves and what physique
competitions they've won in, and, "Oh,
I've been an IFBB pro for..." No one
cares. Landing pages.
Hit me up with questions.
Jayden.
[logo booming] Getting traffic.
It's difficult.
What are your story views at the moment?
Because what's your following, 10,000?
So the only issue
that we might face with this is,
if you're not
getting that many views to your landing
page, especially not nibbles, it
could be that some of that 10,000
are a subprime audience,
that you've got those
followers through doing challenges
and they followed Jayden the challenge
guy.
They followed Jayden the pizza guy.
They followed the guy
that works for Domino's.
They didn't follow the person who's a
personal trainer.
So it might be rather than looking at it
and going, "Oh, I've got 10,000 followers
and none of them are doing business with
me," it could be looking at the fact, and
I've just done this with my big YouTube,
right, where I'm like, I've all these
fucking subscribers, and I'm like, "Oh,
they're the wrong people." They're the
wrong fucking people,
and it's my fault for making the wrong
content.
So now I'm now working on a new channel
where I just want the right people.
So it could be just doubling down on
putting out content at people
that would go to
your landing page,
because you might have just cultivated an
audience of people
that maybe just aren't right,
or they can't afford it, or they have
too many personal trainers all trying to
do the same thing at the same time.
I mean,
how many views would you get per campaign
to the landing page?
Do you look at the clicks from that?
Say like, "Okay,
I'm going to do this story.
Look how many views I get.
I'm going to run this email campaign.
How many clicks?" What would you say
is the, in the sales funnel, where's the
barrier? Okay, what's the email list at?
Rookie numbers.
There could be something
that we could do to really fucking bolster
those numbers
up,
because you don't have the leverage now to
force traffic to that
site enough.
And going from socials to landing page
is going from
dancefloor to fingering.
Get them a drink first.
You know what I mean?
So I think that we do need to go through
the stages, because this is the reality,
right?
When I'm messaging a girl on Hinge
and we've matched, which I don't do
because I'm in a relationship,
let's be real.
You both want to fuck,
or you wouldn't have matched.
You just wouldn't.
But there are stages necessary to go
through before fucking to make sure
that both people are happy
that they're fucking the right person.
Same in business, right?
If someone's following your page,
I'm not saying everyone
that you're following wants to fuck you,
but there's some kind of synergy there.
But when someone gets to your email list,
you're close.
You're walking out the club with
that person.
You just got to make sure you don't fuck
it up at this point.
And sometimes it is too much of a leap to
go from socials to landing page.
It is a little bit too much.
It's one drink. Come on, let's go.
They're like, "Whoa,
I've just met you." So
I would say focus on that,
because they might need so many different
points of
contact from you before they're ready to
buy, or they're ready to go to the landing
page,
or they're ready to watch your video.
Well, actually,
I'm saying it could be a subprime
audience, but now that I know the
size of your email list,
I would say it's not the audience,
it's more to the size
of the email list. 120 people.
Out of those, like you say,
a few of them are just
marking them as unread.
And you might even be going, "Oh,
fucking 50 people read
this." Maybe it didn't.
Maybe it's only 12.
So I think that if you were to tenfold
or at least, yeah,
tenfold your email list,
that would only take you to 1,000.
That's only 10% of your overall following.
Facebook, how many followers?
You're now at 11K. TikTok, 15,100.
The discrepancy's there. If we
were to map this out as an image,
you would say the
choke hold is at the email list.
It's difficult because you still can be in
your infancy, not knowing where you're
going to get your best return on
investment, because if you knew,
you wouldn't have
asked the question. Because
if you knew it was your landing page,
you'd do your
landing page. If you knew it
was your emails, your emails, and
if you knew it was
your socials, you'd do your socials.
And the question, my response is,
I don't know, but you can never give up on
the content side of things,
because all it takes
is one week without posting and
you fucking get in a hole,
and then you just get paralysis.
I've been there so many times.
And do you know what?
I can do massive lines of coke,
and I'm fine.
No come down. I don't post for three days,
I can't come up with ideas, I'm terrible
to be around. Right?
My values for what makes me happy,
productivity
and creativity is one of them.
When I can't think up of content ideas,
I'm
miserable. My missus,
she has to give me a wide berth.
I'm like,
"I've got no ideas for content." She's
like, "You think so?" I'm like,
"Don't gaslight me." All right?
[laughing]
Don't gaslight me.
It's one of those things,
but you always need to make sure
you're flexing the creativity muscle.
Because the subpar email list
and the subpar landing page sounds like
it's working,
but do not stop on the content side of
things, because that's the hardest part.
It's niche, though, as well, right?
ADHD coaching.
It's because you're borderlining in this
territory where people go, "That's not
even a thing." Right?
Do you know what I saw yesterday?
Fat loss advice for lesbians.
[laughing]
I was like, mate, 100%.
I'd say I've seen a definite improvement
over the last few months.
Maybe it will just come together.
Maybe the emails will just improve.
Maybe the standards will just improve.
I'm not sure, to answer your question,
where you should put the effort.
But maybe spend a bit of time improving
emails, see what happens to the bottom
line. Spend a bit of time on content,
see what happens to the bottom line.
But,
it sounds bad, right? If it's working,
let's say we have
engagement,
7% of them sign up to email list, of that,
1%
click the landing page, out of that,
0.3% end up buying.
Even if your conversion rates
are pretty shit,
if we just pump loads of volume in
the top of the funnel through going viral
a bit, it will still trickle through.
The same way that when I knocked on doors,
my close rate was 1%, which
sounds bad,
but my manager would say to me,
"Knock on fucking 100 more doors."
And I'd be like, "Uh." And he'd be like,
"100 more doors." Fuck off.
It's the same. Even
if the conversions could be better,
if they're still
at that rate,
you could just put more content out
and just get people to trickle
through it. Even if you need
1,600 people to read an email to make a
sale, double the amount of traffic,
double the amount of clients.
Okay, first thing before that,
I just love Leadpages.
I'm not paid by Leadpages.
I just love them.
And I see people doing it on Wix.
Shit house. I see them try
and do it on MailChimp. Shit house.
I can spot it a mile off. Second thing,
ladies will know about this,
dudes in here have no idea about color
palettes. Right?
Women, they come in, they're like,
"Whoa." Because I'm a boy, right?
I buy bedsheets. They're like,
"This does not go with the room." I'm
like, "What do
you mean doesn't go with the room?" I had
one housemate who I thought was gay
because he came in blackout drunk once
and we'd decorated the front room.
He could barely talk, and he went,
"The pillows don't go with the room." I
was
like, I've never heard a man say
that before.
But,
even you can go onto Adobe,
there's a color wheel where you can pick a
color and
it'll give you other palette colors
that go with it. Men have no idea. Right?
So I'm seeing red and black. I'm like,
these are the colors of sex and violence.
I'm like, get rid of that.
I had another lad this week using pink.
I was like,
"Do you just work with women?" He's like,
"No, I work with mostly men."
I'm like,
"Why'd you pick pink?" So picking
something like
Leadpages,
not only gives you good analytics,
it has good base
palettes for colors to keep it simple.
Then I've got people that
are putting images behind text.
I'm like, why would you try
and make text harder to
read? Or they're using Times New Roman,
tiny font, or there's just too much, or
there's not line breaks,
or whatever it is.
So from a design perspective,
it needs to look nice, and that's
why I do like the templates
that you get through some of the pre-made
websites.
For me, the pre-made templates work well.
Even if they've seen that template before,
it doesn't matter because it's all about
the experience of someone landing on it.
Definitely video up top.
People sometimes think their brand
is more important.
It's like JB Fitness and a dumbbell.
I'm like, get that the fuck off.
It's just another thing in the way.
Just get that header video dead.
Doesn't need a thumbnail. Also,
sales videos don't need to be over-edited.
They don't need to have transitions
and swish.
Raw, chilled, talking to someone.
Where on socials,
you do need to have a level of editing
or whatever.
I think sales letters, VSLs,
just need to be chilled.
Just you talking to the person
and just letting them know, hey, this
is what I do,
this is why I think it could help, this
is why I think you'd be right, here's the
money-back guarantee,
would love to see you in the program.
Cheers.
Even when you see people who sometimes
are overly in
character online, even myself sometimes,
when it gets to a sales video on a landing
page, I'm chilled. Like Gregg Doucet,
"Hey, guys, wah." But then
in real life, he's just chilled.
It's like, yeah, Gregg, whatever.
Don't make them too long. Again,
better someone wanting more information
that
contacts you, "Hey,
I just want to know how long I actually
need to work with you
to get here." Cool. Reach out to me.
Don't try and over-deliver every single
thing that person would need, because
they're probably just going to start
scrolling and just bounce. What else?
I'd say they're the main components.
The video is so important.
I didn't realize until I started putting
them in some of the ones, especially
when you can verbalize a money-back
guarantee as well.
And just don't cringe, be like, look,
not everyone I work with loves it.
They don't.
And for that reason, if you don't love it,
I'll give you money back.
And people go, fucking hell,
this person's real.
This person's given me an out.
This person's actually honest with me.
You can even make up a statistic.
I'll be honest,
90% of people choose to get a
refund. Why is that? Well,
maybe it's work ethic,
maybe it's finances,
whatever it is. But
if you're part of the 91%, see you inside.
I would have an onboarding call.
So let's say people should have questions
when
they join your program,
but I don't like the idea of being on a
call with someone
who might not do business with me
when it's much more likely
that I get them to
join and then I over-deliver.
And then also,
let's say you do the onboarding call,
I don't want to turn up to a call thinking
I
have to sell them.
I want to turn up to a call going,
"Welcome. Excited.
Tell me about yourself.
Send me a video of your home gym setup.
Tell me what you want to do. Why
is that?" Challenge them,
have a bit more fun.
And even just that interaction
is so much better.
I even found that
when I onboarded clients, I'd say,
"Send me a video of yourself."
And they'd get petrified.
And I would be like,
I could actually tell what program
I'd write them from the video they sent.
So someone would be like,
"Hi, my name's Lucy.
I fucking hate doing these video."
So I already know in her program,
she's going nowhere near a squat rack.
I'm going to be getting her to goblet
squat with a kettlebell because I know the
dumbbell that she wants
is probably a 12 or 14 kg,
and I know the meatheads are
going to want that one.
So like you get to learn the person
that you're speaking
to.
I never got on board with the idea of
having to try and
close someone when I could just send them
to a place that could do it for me.
Whatever they ask as a question,
just sell them a money-back guarantee.
"Oh, James,
I've been in mentorship..." Because it's
not actually the question they have about
the program, it's a question about trust.
That's what they're trying to fish out.
Am I wasting my time and money?
That's really the only thing people care
about.
That's it.
And if you can just remove all the
hesitations that they have, great.
Like even,
if someone, say I'm walking somewhere
and someone's like, "Oh, James,
I'm thinking
about joining your mentorship." They're
actually kind of asking me to sell them
into it.
They're kind of asking me to take away all
the insecurities they have.
I'll just tap them on the back
and be like.
Or if they've been stung before,
I'll say to them,
"Six-month money-back guarantee.
Here it is in writing." And they're like,
"Six months?" I'm like, "Yeah, you can
fucking rip everything off from the
course." And like I say, I'm
transferring the risk from them to me.
And then they go, "Oh, that's nice.
No one else is doing that."
And a lot of the other mentorships do bang
the sales
calls because it is easier for me to say,
"Ring that cunt"
than it is to talk about color palettes,
video sales letters, stories,
links, analytics, conversions, traffics.
Just telling people to jump on a call with
someone means you don't have to get
better at all that stuff.
But it's not scalable.
And again, there are people here
that might only have a few thousand
followers, and
I'm talking to them about how to make
elite content and hide their microphones.
It's overkill, but I want to plan
and set you up for where you
are in three years'
time, not now. Because if I get you,
and I just get you guys all good at
fucking
bashing people on the phone,
what happens when you run a challenge with
people and 48 of them want to jump on a
call, and then you've got
so many things going on in your life.
I just don't think it's congruent with
success long term.
And I know Sean loves his sales calls.
I say, "How many are you doing,
brother?" You know like,
I don't see the sales call button on
glean.com. You know what I'm saying?
And I've been on the website.
I see you hiding your prices, brother.
Get them on the email list first.
I see your sales funnel, brother.
You know what I mean?
[dramatic sound] Do you know what?
It does the same thing,
but I've just never used ClickFunnels.
Like it's pretty much the same thing.
And they appreciate
that dudes don't know color palettes.
They appreciate that men have no design.
Like for dudes, yeah, we have TV,
biggest we can fit in the room,
sofa right in front of it,
wet wipes in the toilet, that's it.
[laughing] All right.
That's all we care about.
Women are like, "Nah,
we need a throw on the sofa." You're like,
"What does this
even do?"
So websites like that
are great because it just takes away all
the shit we're not
good at and allows us to put things in it.
But yeah, a good landing page,
makes all your problems go away.
Then any inbound stuff you get, even
if you just set up a chatbot
that responded
to every single DM, "Hey, sorry, this
is an automated message.
I'm incredibly busy at the moment.
I'm probably with my child,
coaching someone,
or working with my clients.
I would love to get back to you
one-to-one.
But in the meantime, if you
are considering working with me,
here's a website you
can click on that will answer every
question you have.
Maybe see you inside,
maybe not." [dramatic sound]
One thing,
this is a little trick I haven't told too
many people about.
All my webinars I've done,
I'm reading a teleprompter.
So it's a live stream,
but no one knows I'm reading a
teleprompter.
I spend about six hours writing the entire
webinar, so
that when people see me live, they go,
"Fucking hell, this guy knows this
subject well." And I can then do a fucking
long paragraph without
breaking stride.
And then it also means
that my call to actions from the webinar
are regimented throughout it.
So you could write like a long piece,
whatever
it is, because actually what I'm doing
is I'm creating a long-format
video that is just being presented as a
live stream webinar that we're getting
people into,
but I know then it's going to be evergreen
afterwards.
So let's say you would hammer organic.
"Hey, guys, just so you know,
there's a free webinar.
It could change your life.
Drop a jean size webinar.
Drop a dress size webinar," whatever it
is.
You could then spend a bit of time
rehearsing, pre-recording, whatever it is.
You can get apps on iPads,
that then sit beneath the camera with a
little mirror.
There's a company called Newer
that do these like little iPad holders.
So then you have a little clicker
that clicks on it.
Ed from Film Booth, Creator Booth,
all scripted.
Have you noticed he has a clicker in his
hand?
Russell
Brand. No, Russell Brand, the guy from,
what's the film?
You sound like you're from London.
What's it called?
"Forget to Tell Marshall."
Yeah, "Forget to Tell Marshall."
Is it Russell Brand?
That's the right guy, isn't it?
Teleprompter.
Have you ever noticed
that he's got really amazing speech where
he's like, "This
far libertarian,
neoliberal person from the right,"
and you're like, "Fuck, this
guy says...
He's reading a teleprompter." Tucker
Carlson, reading a teleprompter.
Every motherfucker. Iman Gadzhi,
reading a teleprompter.
I don't even think
that he made the script he's reading.
He's just a puppet.
You see it on the news, right?
When you're on the news, they're like,
"73-year-old
from South Brisbane found brutally mu..."
They're reading.
Everyone online in media is just reading.
Because guess what?
To get people to say exactly what they
need to say is fucking difficult.
Even professionals can't do it. So
when it comes to doing a webinar, you can
freeball here and there, but
if you had a structured, written plan that
you read intermittently between it.
Here's another thing we do.
Fuck it, you guys are here.
When people are asking questions,
he's in the back
end knowing which questions I answer best,
and then he texts them to
me to read out on the webinar.
The whole thing is curated to look
really raw,
but to really have the most impact.
So again, if you
were going to do like a live stream,
again, this is where it comes
down to like over-delivering,
overworking on it.
People being like, "Oh,
the guy's just on here spitting questions
and answering."
No. Premeditated. Five grand in paid ads.
Like everything geared up towards this one
video, because it could be worth so much
to your business and time.
And then here's another thing as well.
So let's say you do run paid ads,
and you're like,
"I'm going to put £500 into
signing up for this webinar." All the
people that don't turn up still get
emailed
an offer. So that's it. The data is king.
All of the people watching IFS live stream
and you don't think they're getting an
offer to the mentorship? Shut up.
All of you in here, if you're like,
"James,"
don't worry, you'll be getting an email.
Don't worry,
I've got all your email addresses.
None of you are getting out of here,
even the people in the mentorship,
I'll sell
you again.
[dramatic sound] Yeah,
so one thing we were talking about
which is really good
about journaling is a really powerful
thing that people get a lot out of.
It's one of those things
that people know if they did it,
they'd probably feel
better. Yeah, I think having
that physical product,
I think just selling it and
just saying, look.
At the end,
I'll just attack them a little bit and go,
"You don't spend any time
considering or thinking about the way you
feel.
If you buy this fucking physical item
that my mom's going to post to you," she's
still doing them,
"you're going to fucking feel better.
And if you don't, let me know,
I'll refund you." Whatever it is.
I think just having something punchy like
that.
Even one of my mates who is
football fan, drunk hooligan,
same guy who said about the pillows,
he got a few beers in him. He said to me,
he was like, "Started a gratitude
journal." I was like,
"Excuse me?" He goes, "I wake up,
I've got to write down
three things I'm grateful for." He goes,
"I feel amazing." He
goes,
"I'm thinking about the things I'm
grateful about." He would be the first
person out of all my friends to go, "Huh,
gay." He loves it.
[laughing] Loves it, mate. So,
yeah,
just when you get to the end of
automation, you'll be like,
I've done this to
make you think, to make you do,
to make you do whatever.
Now you should say even something like,
"I've done everything I can.
I now need you to make yourself feel
better.
And the way you can do that
is to buy this." Yeah, I think it's cool.
I still want to see the bit of content
with your mom in it.
You live in Dubai, yeah?
Your mom's actually physically help
posting the journals.
Yeah. For the summer I'm back in Ireland,
though, going back to 49 North.
I think that's great content. Be like,
"Hi, it's my mom.
She kind of works for me. So
if you buy this journal, she'll post it.
But don't worry,
I'll look after her." [laughing] "If we
sell enough of them, I'll
take her somewhere nice. All right, Mom,
back to work." [laughing] And I think
that humanizes you as well.
I think the humanizing thing.
So imagine this,
when I surprised my mom coming back
from Australia with my kid,
the one thing that blew up my DMs is
that my mom still
has all my posters on the fridge.
So it was the fact that,
we can have the jet,
we can have all this stuff,
but the thing that humanizes it is
this guy's parents still have the first
things he ever did stuck on the fridge,
newspaper cutouts.
And I think the humanizing side of it
is really good because you
do want to be the professional.
You do want to be the person
that does the hooks,
the landing pages,
hides the mic under the shirt.
But then at the same time, they're like,
"Oh, this is just someone's son.
This is just a family person." I think
that's a really important part of it as
well. Even with the kid.
I think our last challenge for coaching
did
so well, I think it's because I had a kid.
They're like, "Oh, poor guy's fucked.
I might finally join his program.
He's one of us now, just fucking aging,
getting
gray in his beard and shit." So, yeah,
the humanization of it is really good.
Yes, but no one's getting missed out,
don't worry.
How are we looking on time, by the way?
Fucking hell. Pumping, cooking on gas.
Yes.
[dramatic sound] The better you can take
things away from it and help them
understand, it'd be the better. So again,
I joke about fingering.
Because then people go, "Oh,
what the fuck?
Where did that come from?" But sometimes,
like I've always said, no man knows what
it feels like to get fingered.
So you just got to kind of try things out
and watch
for a response.
And that's the exact same thing we do with
social media.
So again,
no one in their right mind would talk
about fingering to get better at
content, but then you can.
I'm not saying it should be a good reel,
maybe more for
a talk that's private. More so,
if you can find something completely out
of context
that relates back to it a bit.
Let's look at spreading calories out
across the week. You say to someone,
"No human being spends the same amount of
money every day.
So why should I expect you to eat the same
amount of calories
every day? Truth is, at the weekend,
we spend way more, and during the week, we
reign it back."
That is an approach you can have with your
calories.
If you want to be Billy Big Balls
and go out and even go to Waitrose,
you can do it
at the weekend, but during the week,
you've got to make up for it or you go
bankrupt. I think having a way
and a means that you
can take someone away from the world of
fat loss and then bring them
back, analogies, metaphors. ChatGPT
is really good for this as well.
So you can go in and be like, "Hey,
I'm making a reel about fat loss.
The props I have available are Skittles,
two pint glasses, and three balloons.
What can I do?" Obviously,
it's not the best response, but you go,
"Give me five
analogies. Give me five metaphors.
Give me five similes." Do you know what?
I couldn't actually give you the
definition dictionary of them.
I get them all muddled up.
So sometimes I'm like,
"Great analogy." They're like,
"It's a metaphor." I'm,
"Fuck off." [laughing] So even ChatGPT,
whatever you
can to make it easier, just try
and remove it out of context,
whatever you can.
If you ask for 10 examples,
ChatGPT will give you nine shit ones,
but you'll get
one and you go, "Oh,
that's quite a good one." Yes.
[dramatic sound] So let's say you create
an amazing 11-page PDF.
Imagine if you were to send one page every
day via email with a bit of context
around it and a bit of fun.
Do you know what I mean?
If you're going to go to the effort of
making a massive asset that's 11 pages
long, could we break it up
and give it to them in bite-sized chunks?
Because telling me how to make a spirulina
fucking salad and how
to cook a steak perfectly in the same
thing, I'm like, "What the fuck?" Like,
it's
too much. But if you had an email
which was like, "Hey, here
are three fundamental
things you need to know about salad."
Oils.
What was the thing I asked you on the
call? Yeah, you were like...
Oh, which one was it?
You spoke about something, and I was like,
"Margarine." Oh, yeah, it was in the
Discord. I thought margarine was bad.
Yeah.
It's not. Make it a fucking email.
You know what I mean?
So I think you just get pumping to the
point that you're starting to get loads of
traction with those reels. Your average
is still in the thousands, right?
For the new ones you've been putting out.
Yeah. I see everything.
So then with that,
just get to the point
that maybe towards the end of it, maybe
try a carousel, maybe try a reel,
maybe do something.
Be like, "Hey,
if you thought margarine
was bad for you and
that olive oil shouldn't go on a
salad,
then you're probably making loads of
mistakes.
So if you give me your email address,
I'll debunk those myths." There
was a study
recently about olive oil,
and I think it was even fat loss
or something.
I can't even remember what it was.
But it really changed the way that I was
thinking about olive oil. For me,
it just seems like you're just dousing
calories
on shit and making it worse. But
if someone can get to that soon and
explain to audiences maybe those
misconceptions that we have,
because I guarantee,
I stand here as maybe a bit of a
self-proclaimed nutrition expert,
but I know
there are things you know
that I don't know,
and the only way you're going to allow
me to know the things
that I don't know that you know
is to put it into content.
Because if you were to try
and say to me outside,
talk to me about margarine, I'd
be like, "I don't care." But
if you put it in a reel, I'd be like, "Oh,
that's
interesting." Because that's where I go to
to learn new things. Yeah. Make sense?
Where was the next hand that was up?
[dramatic sound]
How many clients would you need at what
price point to be better off financially?
Doing what I'm doing now,
I need 100 clients.
But then there would be some nuances to
that because in corporate,
you're on PAYE, so that your tax is taken
to go straight to the HMRC
or whatever it is.
Whereas if you were self-employed,
you could be able to potentially
negate some of your tax bills.
So for instance, but if you've got your...
This weekend, are you expensing
that against your side hustle?
Yeah. A legitimate registered business.
So you could still be quite tax efficient
doing both.
Do you want to be in a world where you
don't do corporate anymore?
I'm 40 next year and that
is my ultimate goal.
What dependents do you have?
Four-year-old.
It's tough because I can't tell you here
to quit your job or
whatever,
but at some point you probably will have
to. Yeah.
How much do you enjoy your job? I don't.
I'm working really long hours.
If you were to leave your job,
how hard would it be for you to get
reemployed?
So then why not just fuck it off for a
bit, see what happens?
If you double down into it-
I've got bills to pay. Of course you have.
Of course, I get that. But,
otherwise, what,
we could be here in five years' time,
and you go, "I'm still in
corporate." I go, "Well, imagine this.
In my mind, there's only one way out.
You know that way out as well.
You're just looking for someone else to
confirm it.
But, ultimately without you doing it,
maybe next year you go, 'Do you know what,
James? I quit corporate, didn't work out,
went back into corporate.'" Even the job
you go back into might be higher paid,
you might enjoy it more, and you might do
less hours.
Doing the same thing right now,
I just don't see that as congruent
with your goals. And also, imagine this.
If you look at sometimes people's careers
or you look at people's lives or
whatever, whenever there is a bout
or a period of really fucking
impressive shit,
it's usually after something shit.
People have a breakup,
they get an amazing fucking revenge body.
People's business goes under,
the next business,
they float onto the fucking stock
market. Right now,
your capacity for being really impressive
is
hindered by your job.
You might surprise yourself as to how
quick you get those 100 clients
when you need to.
But right now, you don't need to,
and that's the biggest problem.
Like,
when I started PT-ing on the gym floor,
or actually even better yet,
before my
career skyrocketed, I
was stuck in a dilemma that
if I didn't make
more money,
I had to move back home to my parents in
the UK.
And having that hot,
spicy poker up my asshole every single
morning, I
got out of bed like,
"If I don't make today my bitch,
I'm moving home to
Winkfield." There's not a lot going on in
Winkfield.
I like my mom and dad, but
when I get back from Australia, I'm like,
so good to see my family.
By 9:00 PM, I'm arguing about politics.
By two days later, I'm bored.
I was not going back to Winkfield. And
if you leave the corporate world, the only
person that determines whether
or not you go back is you.
So I do think you should do it.
So I've thought about going to PT on the
gym floor
as well. Oh, yeah.
When you quit corporate,
you need to be somewhere that you can
fucking just pepper people all day.
Because doing it online means
that you might not have...
And you can slow the bleeding being a
face-to-face PT as well, especially
if your
demographic could be very similar to
yourself.
Because you say you're 40, female,
training with females.
If I was a 42-year-old female
that wanted to get in shape,
I'd much rather you came
up to me than some of the younger pretty
ladies, no offense. You know what I mean?
Because the 22-year-olds come up with the
Gymshark leggings and they go, "You don't
know what I'm going through."
But the pretty ladies of you that
are 22 in
Gymshark leggings, the chicks that
are doing the barbell hip thrust
incorrectly
that are 19,
they're probably going to hire you because
you look like the people.
Not the old ugly ones.
But ladies 40s going into 50s,
perimenopause, menopause, all of that
stuff, amazing,
and sometimes financially in a much more
safer place to invest in things like
coaching. You know what you need to do.
It's scary, of course. But even
if you monumentally fuck up,
you get reemployed. Just try
and get some coverage so that you
maybe have one or two months' worth of
money to be able to cover bills.
But you're never going to be able to see
what the impressive thing is that you want
to do unless you do it. Otherwise,
you're... All right, here you go.
No problem gets better over time.
Tooth ache.
If you don't address that motherfucker,
you're going to have a really bad few
weeks
and months. When people
are unfit over time, time
decays everything.
However you feel about your situation now,
it's only going to
get worse unless you change it.
Pull the tooth out.
It'll be unpleasant,
but in a few months' time, you go,
"Fucking hell, it was
amazing." Bit like a toxic relationship.
They never just get better.
You're never like, "Oh,
my husband used to beat me
and now things are all right."
[laughing] It never happens.
So you know what you need to.
It's going to be scary.
Do you have a partner?
What did he say about it?
That's also your complaint because I'm
carrying him.
Oh,
dear oh dear. You could hire him
and make him your bitch when you get busy,
though.
[laughing]
What does he do? Bike fitter. Bike fitter.
Interesting. Get rid of him as well.
I'm joking.
[laughing]
The only issue I have,
I'll come to you in just a second, is that
imagine
I'm getting married in Ibiza next year.
I've not dropped a knee yet.
I only drop knees for single legs. But
let's say I get married
and someone's like, "Oh,
there's this amazing
photographer." I go, "Sweet."
And I go to hire him, and he's like,
"Yeah, I'm actually a tax accountant,
but I do wedding photography in my spare
time." I'm like,
"You're coming nowhere near my wedding,
brother, because you're a
fucking part-timer." Like, "Oh,
there's this yoga instructor." And she's
like, "Oh, yeah,
I actually work in Lululemon,
but I teach yoga on the side." I'm
like, "Well, you can't be
that good at fucking yoga." Yeah.
The hindrance to your business as well
is that you're an accountant that does PT,
and it's always going to be
that way until you're not.
You wouldn't even be able to look someone
in the eyes and say, "I'm a personal
trainer," because you know deep down
that you're only kind of a personal
trainer.
Yeah. Oh, you're fucked now.
You're quitting. Call him up now.
Get him on the phone.
[laughing]
Get him on the phone. Yes, the question.
I have one more.
That's all right.
You're dressed very smartly.
Thank you very much.
I like that.
I get the linen to linen hour.
Yeah. I see you.
I would always have a Facebook group for
paid clients because what a lot
of people come to you for
is a training program.
The reason they stay
is they get community.
So some people want to work out,
but they're really hungry for community.
They come into your Facebook group,
they get the workout,
they find a community.
You go, "Hey,
pay my program." They're like, "Why?
So I get a new program?
I'm already part of the community." I
don't agree or think it's the most optimal
way to do it,
because now you're running two groups.
One paid and one not paid.
So, I join you right now,
I get a training program, I get put in a
group, and you say, "Hey,
pay me." How much is it? 897. 897?
I think I'll stick with the free one,
thanks. You know what I mean?
I get it, but at the same time,
I just don't see the point.
Two Facebook groups,
it's just confusing me.
How many clients you got on 897?
I've got, like, 30. That's all right.
That's decent. It's going well.
Making a bit of cashish. Okay. So, this
is another thing
that I see people making a
big mistake with.
You want commitment periods.
Six month minimum, three month minimum.
You want it because you're worried they're
just going to leave.
But if you offer a money-back guarantee,
they're just going to fucking leave
anyway, right? So maybe don't make
that amount.
Because also, 897, I'm suddenly thinking,
fucking hell, it's nearly 1,000 pounds.
Whereas you to say 75 pound a week,
you could even then start to collate it or
make it a lot closer to some of the costs
that they're thinking about with coaching
anyway.
You go to your local PT at the gym
and see him twice a week, oh, it's going
to cost you 80 to 120 pounds.
Mine's only 75.
And with that,
you don't just get two workouts,
I'll write you five, and only three
of them are at the gym,
and I'll check in with you every day.
Then you can start to make your offering
look a little bit closer.
And again, I don't know if this
is wrong or right,
I love taking these big costs
and making them seem smaller,
and also just saying to someone, "Hey,
just give me
your first week's payment." Because other
coaches exactly like you, not
exactly like you, not wearing linen
or whatever,
but other coaches out there are
looking to do the exact same thing.
And the person that says, "Oh, yeah,
just pay me. It's this much a week.
You can pay me in advance if you want,
but ultimately, my program's fucking
awesome.
I don't need to get a grand off you up
front." It's just one of those
things where also, this event, IFS,
you would be surprised how many personal
trainers, business owners, people
that can literally go up to people in a
room full
of weights and ask them for cash,
do not have 1,000 pounds.
How many people did the payment plan?
A lot.
Maybe like 80% of people
that have businesses,
we've never had so many
fat people,
and personal trainers do not have 1,000
pounds
to piss out of. So,
when you're creating a fitness program for
general populations
that have just regular jobs,
their families, independence,
everything else,
sometimes some people get to that point.
They go, "Fuck, I'd love to do
that program.
I just don't have 800 pounds." But
if you were to say, "Oh, it's 300 a month,
or
it's this, or it's this,
or it's this," you could also reduce the
barrier to entry.
And I think that is also another kind of
powerful tool that people need to look
into,
because you're just looking to mitigate
risk.
You just don't want people to waste your
time.
But at the same time, if I said,
"You might get a few more time wasters,
but
loads more revenue," you'd probably do it.
We do this quite a bit, actually.
If you were to send out an email,
how many are on your email list?
I've got, like,
600 people. Cool. I'm not emailing it,
though. Okay.
But you've got 30 customers. So,
if you were to leave this room today
and go, "Hey,
guys, do you know what?
I'm scrapping this 897.
I'm actually just going to make it a
monthly payment.
So, the offer is,
it's 300 pounds for your first month,
which
is pro rata what it'd be anyway.
I'm going to do your program,
add you to the
community.
I'm also going to extend the money-back
guarantee from two weeks to a
month. The reason I'm doing this is,
I want you in the program to see how great
it
is. You either love it,
or I'll refund you your money." You could
probably close 40
or 50 people tonight from that one email.
"I'm trialing this out.
I'm not sure how it's going to go.
I could regret it.
So, for the next five days,
I'm going to reduce the barrier to entry,
so you only
need 300 pounds to be in my program,
not 900." Either way, you earn the same
money, you just get more sales.
You might have some time wasters,
but you just look
like a fucking G, because you're like,
"Hey,
don't worry about it." Someone joins,
does a couple weeks, waste your time.
Don't worry, I got 50 clients last week.
It doesn't matter. So,
that's something I would maybe consider.
Facebook group, gone. Barrier to entry,
down. Yeah. Just a bit more risk.
You seem like a young chap.
You live at home with your parents? Yeah.
Yeah, I've seen it from your content.
I see your kitchen.
That's not a boy's kitchen.
That's a family kitchen.
Yeah, it's one of those things
that I'd be like, they're just some ideas.
It's just a question you could ask people.
It's a campaign initiative
that you could run to potentially make
three grand
tonight,
and we could spend it all out tonight on
booze and going out.
We could do anything you want. But yeah,
the barrier to entry, when I hear 1,000
pounds, I'm thinking fuck it.
My mentorship, why I help you, is
cheaper than your coaching. I'm rich,
don't worry.
But I don't want Sean Casey here, "Oh,
look at me." Got to play it cool.
See this drink? Don't worry about it.
I'm good.
I'm
flying back BA, but still. All right.
No,
it's one of those things where optics
again, 897 pounds is going to make a
lot of people feel ill.
Your coaching could be amazing.
I'm sure it is.
But for me,
that just seems like an unnecessarily high
boundary to get people into
your program.
Because someone might need your help,
they just don't have 800 and
fucking 90 quid.
Neither did I after my Amex bill after
Vegas. Yeah.
I didn't have 800 pounds. I was like,
"Fucking hell." But yeah, so it's just
something to consider.
I'm not asking you to charge less.
I'm asking you to give people more
options.
I'm asking for you to be more vulnerable
on your end so that people can actually
buy the thing that you're selling.
[whooshing sound]
So,
for the 3,000 email addresses you have,
don't send them back up the
funnel. You can,
I just don't think it ever looks
that great when you go
get an email and someone's telling you to
go to social media.
You're like, "Mate,
I've literally just come from social
media.
I've just been scrolling my life away.
I've come here to pay off my Amex
and go through my bills." Well,
I tell you what.
Let me interrupt you. Sorry about this.
Those 3,000,
I want you to sell to them so hard
that list
becomes 200. Buy or die.
Just hammer the fuck out. Diran, right?
Is he in here?
Diran's Turkish email list.
How many has he got?
400,000 people on the email list.
I go, "Diran,
do you know what would be better?
200,000,
where 200,000 people have unsubscribed,
but you now have
10,000 more fucking clients." He's more
worried about losing email addresses than
he is about making fucking money. So,
that 3,000,
do you know what it sounds to me
like? They've not been sold to enough.
Because if they had- I have a new-
Buy or die. Buy or die. Buy or die.
And the other ones,
the bigger list, the 10,000, oh no,
10,000 followers to go onto the
list,
maybe just run some kind of frequent
campaign or maybe even
a paid ad, because your paid ads
are doing quite well for the growth,
right? Cool.
Could we not, for just a little period,
spend that 50 a day on getting email
addresses? Maybe too soon.
They've only had one point of contact
at this point.
So maybe,
is there not an initiative where we could
say, "Hey, let's take that 50
euros a day and let's put it into a
campaign to go to existing followers to
get
their email address."
And you could even have a video going,
"Hey, I see that you
follow me. I really appreciate that.
What I'd love to do
is to open a line of communication over
email.
If you don't like them,
you can unsubscribe after the first one."
Because you're
paid
Our ad stuff at the moment
is going towards growth,
when really it might want to go
towards conversion. Even if we just,
it's like a bulk and a cut.
Maybe we stop bulking for a bit
and we do a bit of a cut for a bit.
We spoke a little bit about pricing
structures.
Another point that's kind of really
fucking,
and we're never going to get through
all of this.
We spoke about it a little bit before.
Those of you with smaller accounts,
I never heard of this terminology till
earlier
this year,
but so much of what you're looking to do
with content is accrue
goodwill. If your call to actions
are falling flat on their face,
it's because you
are not putting out enough good content
that's having a meaningful impact with
people. Because if you can turn up
and revolutionize someone's life with your
content all the time. Sean Casey again,
love using him as an example.
He made so many amazing reels, and he got
people to think so much about fat loss,
fitness, and everything, that when he
released a fucking PDF recipe book,
which I
guarantee the majority of people didn't
cook a single
fucking recipe out of,
they bought it as a means of paying
back the goodwill. Sean Casey, literally,
anyone know how much it was?
€27?
I think I worked out he did 40,000 sales
at €27.
He did over a million euros from his PDF
recipe thing, right?
That was people just saying,
"You're a fucking legend.
You've helped me so much.
Let me support you."
When I released my first book,
the majority of people I
don't think even fucking read it.
I think they just went,
"Love your content.
Let me give you something back." So what
you want to do with your content strategy
is accrue goodwill through posting regular
things.
Again, who in here does jujitsu,
apart from yourself? Cool.
Have you ever bought an instructional
before where you're like, "Craig Jones,
you're a fucking legend." Buy your
instructional, never use it.
But you're just literally trying to put
money in the pockets of the athletes who
you respect and you like. So,
so much of your content strategy, even
if you don't
do call to actions for weeks
or maybe months on end, just rest safe
knowing that you are accruing goodwill
within those people, and then
when it comes
to the point that you're relaunching your
program, whatever it is, that they will
buy.
I think that's such a good mindset to get
in when thinking about
what it is you're doing. Because
if you're just posting stuff
and you're like, "Oh,
I haven't done a call to action in a
while.
I haven't asked anything of my audience."
Just know that you're building this
invisible force within strangers where
they will feel compelled at some point
to give you their money. Now,
I just want to make sure I don't miss some
of these
things. But what I'm going to tell you,
we were supposed to talk about this more.
I've made an underrated category
and an overrated category,
and I want you guys to maybe challenge me,
disagree with things, question me,
and we'll make that the Q&A for the last
half an hour.
So,
things I think are overrated right now in
our industry, asking for follows.
Other things I think are overrated
is putting too much energy into TikTok.
I do not think the platform has matured
enough yet for us to reap.
I like to think that so many different
social media platforms are like planting
seeds that we can harvest later.
I think on Instagram,
you can plant some seeds
today and harvest in nine months time.
I don't think TikTok is there yet.
I think TikTok is only at the place where
the real place to get sales from it is
TikTok Shop,
which you would need a product for.
It's the weirdest landscape at the moment
where basically for Nutonic, people are
like,
"You need to be using TikTok shop."
And there are people out there that are
like, "Oh my God, I found this drink
and it's really helped me" product,
they get
£3.50 commission a thing. I think
that doing gym content, talking about
muscle growth
is overrated unless you
are fucking jacked because you are
just opening yourself to get torn down
and ripped apart.
And those of you talking about it
are doing it because other creators
are doing
it, and they're also getting torn down.
It is so difficult to be an authority in
muscle growth.
You are so much better positioning
yourself as talking about the
evidence-based nature of training.
Do not say, "If you want to get jacked,
if you want to get big, if you want
massive arms,
if you want to build muscle." Don't use
those.
"If you want to maximize your bicep
training,
these are some exercises you can do.
If you want to get good variation in your
back training, these are the three grips
that are important." Make it about the
evidence-based training
principles.
Do not make it about absolute muscle
growth, because even the
hooks are in the framing of the wrong
place.
If someone was in financially really bad
trouble and tried talking about making
money.
This is why I don't trust financial
advisors, right?
Financial advisors are like,
"If you give me your money,
I can make you rich." I'm
like, "Yeah,
but you make your own money
and you're not rich, because if you were,
you wouldn't be asking me for my money to
make you rich." You know what I mean?
You ever feel that? They're like,
"I'm an expert in managing wealth."
Where's yours
then? Anyway,
that's a whole fucking other thing.
Overrated, PDF squeeze pages. Overrated,
training plan
squeeze pages. Overrated,
read caption posts where you're
just trying to do some six-second fucking
video like, "Read the caption.
Read the caption." Hate it.
Wearing vests in content.
I know I'm wearing a vest today,
we're in Ibiza, right?
Tom Bailey PT,
always wore this like Lululemon fucking
beta.
I was like, "Mate, you look like a cunt.
You look like a cunt because you're not
big, you're not jacked." Also, if you have
tattoos or... It's obvious, right?
There's that fucking Pat O'Dwyer guy who
literally goes like this,
"Oh, yeah, guys, I'm fucking..." Like
when he's doing content.
I know what you're doing, bro.
You're just trying to show off your traps.
It's fucking shit. If you want to dress,
plain T-shirts, don't
wear shit on it.
Darren did an event in Manchester wearing
a Marvel T-shirt, and it
was like the most colorful fucking thing
ever.
And people I could just see
were just staring at his T-shirt
and not listening to
him. Presentation,
look professional in some respects.
If you're going on a first date with a
girl, you wouldn't wear a vest, so don't
fucking do it in your videos.
If you're doing some training stuff, cool.
But again, it's one of those things,
just little changes.
Not wearing Grenade T-shirts, all right?
Are they paying you? No.
Then don't fucking wear it. Lululemon,
good man. That was expensive.
It's all right. I paid for it. So,
sales calls versus objection handling,
underrated.
Having your video eight mile the shit out
of them, just objection
handle everything beforehand. Overrated,
talking about yourself.
Overrated, free rent in gyms. Overrated,
paid ads early
in the content game. So,
if you are just starting out in content
and you want to do paid ads, you're
probably not that good at doing content to
do paid ads.
Because if you're someone that's, "Hi,
my name's Josh."
If you can master
and dominate organic content,
when you turn up to do paid
content, it will fucking bang.
You'll get a much better return on ad
spend because
you are more competent, you
are better at using a camera, you
are better at
lighting, setup, everything.
You know in "Fast
and the Furious One" where Paul
Walker uses his NOS too quick? That
is people with paid ads in the
fitness industry.
You want to get as far as you fucking can
with your organic,
then press the nos on the paid ads
when you get to the tail end.
It's not a prerequisite.
It's something you do further down.
Another thing that's overrated,
so there's showing high ticket.
Those of you that
are trying to charge heinous amounts of
money for coaching, I can
see it in your eyes
that you don't even believe it's worth it.
You've just had a business mentor that's
told you it's the way to do it, and
they're just trying to fucking wank
themselves off.
"Yeah,
I helped this guy build £50,000 this
month."
And you're like, "Mate,
they signed them up for six months in
advance high ticket.
You're just making it look like you're
fucking better at your job than you're
not."
Okay. Things I think that
are underrated at the moment,
that I definitely think you
need to double down on. Good audio.
Too many of you using those clippy little
shitty mics.
Did I see you with one of them online?
With the little fluffy bit on it?
I steal the DJI still, mate. No,
you got it. No, I meant behind you then.
It was you. You had the mic, didn't you?
The little fluffy bit on the end.
Is it the cheap one from Amazon? Yeah,
I remember. Yeah, I remember, mate.
I see everything. Don't you forget,
all right?
The £20 ones on Amazon sound like shit.
They sound worse than iPhone.
I know the DJI mics are expensive,
but they
sound fucking good. Audio
is such an important part in this.
Your camera quality can be a bit worse
if the audio is crisp.
So much of what we do on content
and listening to things is audio.
I actually can watch YouTube
when I'm driving because most of YouTube
is listening.
It's not actually watching.
When you do watch YouTube,
it's just the pattern
interrupts to keep your brain happy.
That's why so many of us actually learn
things better when we're doing other
tasks.
We are audio learners better than we even
realize, so please make sure the
quality's good. Underrated,
building your email list.
Underrated, money-back guarantees.
Underrated, autoresponders.
Underrated,
really high-frequency content periods.
For those of you that are time rich,
money poor, Eddie Abu,
although I think he's
a fucking cunt,
was posting 14 times a day for a
long period of time.
You can tell how much
that guy craves attention,
one, through the amount of gear he
was taking as a bodybuilder, but two,
how quick
he changed up his content approach.
If you look at his content like three,
four years ago, he's a real sensible guy
just giving advice. But when
that character came out, it just grew
more on socials,
and people felt they could relate to it.
He then just doubled down, tripled down,
quadrupled down.
He putting out 12 to 14 pieces of content
a day every
day. [screen whooshes] Of
course. But that's still high frequency.
No one really puts out two pieces a day.
Whatever you can do.
But if you're someone that's only got two
clients and you're only putting out one
reel a day,
what are you doing with your time,
brother? You know what I mean?
So the most amount you can get out.
Maybe even it's two posts that
are 6 out of
10 and a repost,
or it's one post that's a 10 out of 11
and it's two
reposts. When you have the time to do it,
just fucking get content out there.
And don't be afraid. Underrated,
reposting.
Again, most of my videos
that have gone viral have been reposts.
And again,
if someone out there sees a post
that you've
reposted, and they go, "Fucking hell,
mate, I've already seen this one,"
probably not going to slip off their
chairs to buy your program for $897.
Whereas the people
that do buy your program,
I guarantee the 30 people that are in
your program at the moment,
are the type of people that go, "Hey, man,
first time
I saw that post, I liked it. This time,
I'm just going to double tap it because I
know what you're doing." They go,
"Get that money, brother.
Get that money." You know the Sidemen,
Chunkz, Yung Filly,
those people on YouTube,
one of the best things they've done
is created an audience
that want them to make money.
I saw Chunkz do a Pringle advert,
and all the
comments went, "Get that money, G.
Get that money. Advertise to us, brother.
We don't care.
Get that cash, Chunkz."
And you want the same, an audience
that when you do repost,
even if it's the third time,
they fucking share it. I love that.
When I saw it three months ago,
I loved it so much,
I'm going to share it again.
And you are only going to push away
dickheads and create a
better audience of people
that want you to do well.
Again, "Friends," how many times has
that been replayed?
You don't see someone going, "I saw
that in 1997." [laughing]
Cool. I enjoyed it in 1997,
and I enjoy it at the bottom of a
comedown.
I enjoyed it yesterday in the bath
listening to sad songs. Whatever it is.
So again, the frequency, underrated.
B-roll voiceovers.
So those of you that are shy,
maybe in the gym, putting together
content. So even talking to camera,
we went through some of this.
You're a weapon. How old are you? 40?
45? 45. Look at that. I see everything.
In the gym, you can do ring muscle ups.
I'm like,
instead of talking to camera where I can
see you're a bit nervous, I want
you talking to me
while I'm watching you do ring muscle ups
at 45, because now
it benefits everything else
that you're doing, and that B-roll just
gives me the authority
that I need to know
that you know what you're on about.
So for those of you that even
if you're on the train or something,
you could even
just mash up a load of content
and be like,
"The most important thing that you do
in training is just turn up,"
or whatever it is that you want to say.
But again, B-roll is just footage.
B-roll can be great.
I'm just saying it can be great. Again,
for those of you that don't know, every
time you're training, even
if you're just setting up your camera,
film some of it,
because there's going to come a time where
you make a video, and when you're
talking about something, you go, "Oh,
I've got a video for that." I've got
16,000
videos in my phone. I know, "Oh,
I've got a video from October 2021.
I could use that." Just having those
assets to overlay, people love being taken
on a journey. I was watching...
There's, what's his name?
"Lost Civilizations" on Netflix,
the bald guy
that thinks there was a hidden tribe,
the advanced civilization.
What's it called? Graham Hancock.
Anyone watch the Graham Hancock thing on
Netflix?
You did watch it, right? But in it,
if you watch it, there
is a scene change every
three seconds. Every three seconds.
You've got an A piece to camera of Graham
Hancock telling his story, which I think
is off a teleprompter. Then three seconds,
drone shot.
Three seconds, Graham Hancock.
Three seconds, Jeep driving down the lane.
Three seconds, something else.
The whole series,
there's no more than three
seconds of one scene before they swap,
and then your brain is like,
wow.
Same in content.
Just keep people's brains moving.
Got some people,
a guy on YouTube called Ryan Humiston,
who just walks around his
gym with a tripod.
He'll put the tripod down.
"The three most important things for
getting jacked shoulders,"
and he can say that
because he's jacked.
He'll go somewhere else. Boom.
"Is that you get the partial range of
motion." Boom.
He'll then sit on the leg extension.
And those little changes
are his pattern interrupts because he's
not using B-roll.
Underrated,
showing off results But not testimonials.
So what I'm saying by this is,
so many people are, "Hi, here's my client,
Becky.
She lost 14 stone
and she worked really hard in the program,
and Becky and I,
we've worked together."
That doesn't work because guess what?
No one gives a fuck.
No one gives a fuck about your client.
Becky gives a fuck because she lost 14
fucking stone, but your prospects don't
give a fuck about a stranger. If I
was to sit here and grab someone from the
crowd
and go, "This guy made 100k," you're like,
"I don't care." But if you can
position your testimonials in a way
that people do care, so for instance,
your hook
could be,
"Is it possible to lose 14 stone in a
year?
And could you do
that without having to count calories
and having breakfast on
three days of the week?" Well, it
is because Becky did it.
And how did Becky do it?
And you could tell a story about Becky
and then position it at the end
that it was
a testimonial of a client. But really,
you are telling a story to make the
person watching it believe it's possible.
You don't just do a testimonial post,
you tell a story.
And in that story,
you make the person watching it believe
they can accomplish the
same thing because that's really what
we're doing.
Whenever I use a case study of one of
people that I've worked with, I'm not
actually trying to show them off,
I'm trying to convince you
that it's possible.
A few more underrated,
then we'll get into Q&A.
[laughs] Another thing underrated,
good expenses.
Again,
you guys are going to run businesses.
There's going to be turnover.
You should invest in kit, equipment,
microphones, things like that.
It can seem like wasted money,
but there is a return on investment to
come from it.
And three case studies I just want you
guys to be aware of before we get into
Q&A. Who follows Sam Seaforth?
Does funny skits, works for
Grenade.
The effort this guy puts into his content,
he films the whole thing on CapCut,
it's all done on his phone.
He'll do a three-hour edit on his phone.
Let me just check if that's his Instagram
handle.
Can everyone do this for me right now on
your phones?
Sam Seaforth, F-O-R-T-H. He's a nice guy.
And let me see if there's a...
He's got his three pinned
posts at the top, but even
if you just click the one with the little
red
things, he does these all on CapCut, and
captions, scene interrupts,
pattern changes.
It makes it seem like it's quite like a...
Sam? How do you spell it again?
Sam C, let's see, F-O-R-T-H. Oh,
sorry.
Yeah. And if you even scroll down,
you see there's a thumbnail
of him holding a medal, right? Yeah.
If you look at just the way he moves the
phone before the video starts, the
pattern, the zoom, the him to her to him,
the
captions to him to her to him.
The effort he puts
into every single transition,
and he does this all on iPhone,
and then he's running
and he's doing stuff,
and he's actually done a video during the
marathon just so he
could have this for his content.
Sometimes when I'm ever feeling like I'm
putting a
lot of effort into content,
I go watch people like Sam
and realize I'm not putting
any effort into it like he is.
The amount of effort that people
are putting into,
we want to be able to be inspired by that.
So I watch Sam Seaforth when I think
that my content is good, and I
realize I'm shit. Another guy
that I spoke about before called Matt
Armstrong with
One T on YouTube. This guy
is buying crash-damaged cars
and fitting them up,
which sounds like a thing
that only dudes are into,
but he's so good at telling
stories that my missus watches it.
My missus is now feeding the baby at home,
watch- she doesn't like cars, but she's
watching it because he's a great
storyteller.
I would love everyone to watch just one of
his videos as your homework, and you
will lose yourself in the fact
that he's telling stories.
So for instance,
he'll buy a secondhand headlight from a
car, but he
won't just go, "Oh,
here's a headlight," and put it in.
He'll be like,
"This has a different VIN number to the
car from here.
And when you buy crash-damaged cars,
sometimes you can plug these in,
and the car
will not let the headlight work because
it's a different part.
This is to stop people stealing them."
And what we've seen in London is people go
around Porsches,
and they steal the headlights because
they're worth so much money.
Then he says, "This cost me £680,
and I just don't think it's going to
work." Then he goes to his dad, "Dad,
do you reckon it's going to work?" "I
don't
think it's going to work." He plugs it in,
it works.
"Come on!" And they're happy about it,
and you're like, "Fucking hell, I'm happy
for this guy. It's just a headlight."
But if he just put the headlight in, we
wouldn't have experienced the whole ups
and downs of it.
Then there's another one where he has an
iPad. He presses start.
We have seven days to get this Nissan GTR
ready because it's going in for a tune.
If we do not get this Nissan GTR ready,
we're going to miss the date.
They go in there,
they're working all night.
It's 3:00 in the morning,
they're changing tires.
Listen,
that guy has millions of pounds
and millions of fucking
subscribers to his channel.
If he wanted to get the car tuned a day
later, it would
be fine.
But he's raising stakes in the story,
making it seem like it's
important. Imagine if you were like,
"I've got to be training.
There's a marathon in 42 days, and
if I don't get ready,
I won't finish the marathon.
And worse yet, I've set the stakes that
if I don't
finish this marathon in under three hours,
I'm going to buy V Shred's program 42
times."
Suddenly, there's a story,
there's stakes to it. It's important.
They're going to do things. What
if it works? What if it doesn't?
Another thing you see,
"Top Gear." We all love "Top Gear." It's
not a
car journalism program. The ones that
are our favorites are the stories.
When they go to Africa,
when they go to Iceland,
and really the reality is they're
just driving from A to B.
But they don't just go from A to B.
There are stakes where
if their car breaks down,
they've got to drive that horrible
car back there. There's B stories.
We've ended up at a racetrack,
we've got a text,
and we've all got to do a drag
race. Everything
that we feel the emotional connections to
are
stories. It's why, not to get too deep,
reason people love
religion, they're just good stories.
Everything is based off stories.
You want to get a million people to go to
war, you best tell a good story.
If you can bring storytelling into your
content, because at the end of the day,
Matt Armstrong is just buying crashed cars
and fixing them.
But that doesn't sound sexy. But
when you tell a good story around it,
it is.
Same when it could be fitness, fat loss,
anything else.
If you can start to watch these
storytellers at work, you can really
appreciate how good their content is.
Another thing that's done really well by
Matt Armstrong is he has a camera
with a microphone on it,
but then he'll cut to scenes where there's
another camera,
and he'll do voiceovers. And then I
was trying that with other bits of content
where I was like,
"Maybe I'll do the first bit of content
talking to the camera.
Then I'll do a voiceover.
Then I'll come back to another bit of
content."
Look at what's working for other people
and try and emulate it.
And the third thing that I would say
is a good case study for you to do,
Adam Sullivan, who's here,
who I had blocked for four years.
I thought he was a cunt Sorry,
he's still blocked on TikTok.
He's now one of my best mates in the
industry.
He is one of the biggest
encapsulations of having a strong brand.
Adam has only 600,000 followers,
which I know is a lot.
Only 600,000 followers.
He's making 1.2 to 1.5 million Aussie
dollars a month.
It's about £500,000, £600,000 a month.
And he's actually only got 4,000
or 5,000 clients, but those clients buy
everything from him.
When he does merch drops,
he does half a million dollars in a
day.
I've never seen a brand so strong on a
creator so
small. He's just a normal guy.
He's no different to you.
He did 10 years in fitness first.
He even used to be a metaller in a rock
band.
So if you can look and epitomize from,
okay, Matt Armstrong tells good stories.
Adam Sullivan has a strong brand.
This person creates this good content.
If you can start taking inspiration from
all of those people and bringing it
towards your own businesses,
you can have so much more pulling power.
You might not have two Lamborghinis like
he does at 34, but still, you
want to be able to take some inspiration
from all those different people and start
applying it to your own.
We'll go into the questions now.
I want you to disagree, challenge me.
Do about 15 minutes,
then I'll piss myself.
We'll go...
No offense.
Can we have a question from someone
that hasn't asked a question yet?
Yes.
So I would say
brand is where your professional identity
meets your
personal identity.
You just have to make sure,
I think we only have 10,
15 minutes left because you want to piss.
So one more time.
Brand is personal
and business identity mixed together.
That's not to say there's a perfect ratio,
but maybe it's 80% business,
20% personal. For instance, now
that I have a child, my brand is
changing because my child
is more involved in it than before.
I'm doing more static images that
are nothing to do with fitness because my
brand
has changed. I think
that you should maybe get a picture in
Ibiza and go, "I'm here partying, but I'm
also here learning how to be a better
coach." So then people don't just think
you're a dickhead. And again, this
is positioning.
If you see a guy in a bar with a gold
Rolex, chances are he's a cunt.
But if you were to sit next to him
and he was to say, "Five years ago, I
was homeless and I was living
on the streets,
but I saw a gap in the market.
I created an empire,
and now I've retired all my parents,
and I bought a gold
Rolex," he's a hero.
It's not the watch that changes,
it's the story around it.
So it's important that all of us,
as far as a brand positioning,
are levering
things like that to make sure it looks
good.
So yeah, if you're in Ibiza, someone goes,
"Oh, it's all right for you." But if
you're here trying to build your business
so you can help hundreds and maybe even
thousands of people feel better,
be healthier or whatever,
suddenly you're a hero.
Picture's the same, story's different.
So just make sure you position yourself
better. Yes.
So I've got a sports tech company.
A sports tech, and the tech is?
Smart clothing for intelligent athletes.
If I was you, so it's tech shorts.
Basically, I put these shorts on,
they measure
my legs. I do some back squats. It goes,
"Yo, James, your right quad's bigger than
your left. Your hip extension
is slow out of wood," whatever it is.
That's really exciting.
Sounds really cool.
I would be keen to get creators to try it.
So maybe you reach out to YouTubers in the
fitness space, people that do things
like try aura rings, whoop straps,
all of this, because there are going
to be people that have a shared interest,
right?
So let's say I'm your generic fitness
YouTuber, and you message me and you go,
"Hi,
James, I've got this pair of shorts
that do this." I might not care about your
business that much,
but do you know what I do care about?
The millions of people
that might be frothing over this.
And then I can make a little movie,
which would be the YouTube video,
talking about
it.
You do open yourself up to potentially
negative criticisms if the product
isn't good enough,
which you wouldn't have control over.
But I think that's a social strategy I
would use where that's what Eight Sleep
did
with the mattress.
They went out to all the YouTubers,
gave them a mattress for
free, knowing the product
was fucking sick.
Now people like me can't shut the fuck up
about it.
But if you were to get people to use it-
Yeah
...
you could then clip their content for your
socials, and then you could say, "If
this is something of interest to you,
we're launching on this date.
Give us your email address
and we'll give you a discount." That's
another thing
that Eight Sleep do.
Eight Sleep have amazing marketing.
When I went to their website, pop up,
it goes, "One-time offer, 10%
off. Give me your email address." So
that even though I bounced from the
website,
which means I didn't buy,
they emailed me every day for 15 days.
Boom, boom, boom, boom. "Claim your offer.
Claim your offer.
Claim your offer." And it
was the money-back guarantee
that got me to buy in the
first place. But yeah,
it's one of those things that
once you get someone to land on your site,
if you can get their contact information
and just say, "Yo, when we drop this,
perform better," whatever it is, you get
their email address. But yeah,
it would be something,
I would have it as some kind
of pop-up on the website.
"This isn't out yet.
Give us your email address.
We'll let you know when it does,
and maybe give you a discount." Sounds
exciting,
though. But yeah, I would say try
and get email addresses,
but you would really
want the product out there,
and I would definitely use high-level
YouTubers
with big followings
and leave something from it. That's cool.
That sounds sick